Good evening everyone. I'd like to call
the February 23rd meeting of the
governing body to order. Madame Clerk,
would you take the role, please?
>> Mayor Collins,
>> present.
>> Dr. Emmens,
>> Mr. Esel,
>> here.
>> Mr. Leborn,
>> Mr. Moody,
>> here.
>> Dr. Renie,
>> present.
>> Mr. Crave,
>> Mr. White,
>> present. Mr. Wolf
>> here.
>> Dr. Aldrich
>> present.
>> All members are present. We do have a
quorum.
>> Would you please join me in the pledge
of allegiance except if you have a
crutch
Number
four, consent agenda. All agenda items
listed with the designation of CA are
considered to be routine items by the
governing body and will be enacted by
one motion. There will be no separate
discussion on these items unless a
member of the governing body so requests
and support by two other members is
received. Any item removed from the
consent agenda will be considered in its
normal sequence on the agenda.
>> All right. Are there any items a member
of the governing body would like to
remove from the consent agenda?
>> Mr. Mayor,
>> Mr. Escoel
>> 19B.
>> That's the utility easement with
Microsoft. We have a substitute for
that.
>> Concur.
>> Second. in concurrence.
>> All right. 19B is removed.
>> Second,
>> Mr. Escoel.
>> 19A.
>> And that is the professional services
agreement with TDSI. We also have a
substitute for that.
>> Concur.
>> All right. 19A is removed. And could we
ask for item? Yes, sir.
>> Uh 14.
>> Thank you. Uh item 14 um is a final plat
and we won't finish the zoning until our
next meeting. So, it would be out of
order. So, I'd ask that that be removed.
>> Concur.
>> Concur. Thank you. So we have 19A, B,
and item 14. Is there anybody else?
>> Hearing none, I would entertain a
motion.
>> So move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White. Motion by Dr.
Aldrich. All those in favor of the
consent agenda, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. The consent agenda is
removed. Approved with 19A, 19B, and 14
removed.
Number 6A, public hearing for renewal
applications for existing city liquor
licenses, retail, restaurant, limited
retail, resort, barrel licenses, micro
brewery, satellite distillery, special
malt, beverage, and winery permits filed
with the city clerk's office.
>> All right. Annually, state law says we
have to renew all of our liquor
licenses, and this is the first step of
that, which is the public hearing. Is
there anybody in the audience that would
like to speak to the renewal of any of
the liquor licenses in our community?
Would
you like to come forward, please? We'd
love to have you.
>> If you do me a favor, just push the
button and pull that microphone so it's
like a m inch or so from your mouth.
That way, everybody can hear you.
>> Perfect.
>> Can you hear us?
>> I can. Introduce yourself, please.
>> Um, my name is AK Wallace. I'm the
district manager for Chibah Hut.
>> And I am Cam or Cameron Brown, the
general manager of Chibah Hut here in
China.
>> Welcome. Um so we just
>> yeah just came up to say that we're
stoked to be a part of Cheyenne. We uh
are glad that uh we're being considered
for renewal and uh so far have had great
success in the community and just
appreciate everybody's support and um
happy to be here.
>> That's great. We were so excited to hear
that you were taking a a building that
was becoming empty and making sure that
it was continuing to be used. So thank
you for that.
Thanks for being here. Anybody else?
How about online, Jennifer?
All right. Anybody on the governing
body?
I guess we must have all been good
behavior this year because there's not a
lot of comments. Uh the purpose of the
public hearing has been met. We'll
assign this item to the finance
committee which will meet next Tuesday.
>> Number seven, ordinance, second reading,
creating chapter 8.72, private displays
on public property to prohibit the
unauthorized use of public property for
specified private displays.
>> All right. Is there anybody in the
audience here today to speak to this
ordinance that uh would limit um
memorials on private or on public
property or rights of way?
>> Good evening, ma'am. Welcome.
>> And if you could just pull that down so
it points right at you. Perfect. Thank
you.
Now, do I need to introduce myself?
>> You do, ma'am. We want to know who you
are.
>> My name is Cheryl Garish, and I live on
the east side of town. And on Nationway,
there is an ongoing display. It has been
there for years now, uh, with flowers
and pictures and lighted up lights at
night of a memorial of a someone who has
passed away. And I feel that it is
inappropriate for this to be in on
public property for long term. Rest of
us have our memorials at cemeteries and
they even clean them off every six
months. And this has been here for
years. And I think it it is not
appropriate for one person to have
and when the in the summer when people
are mo when they're mowing and
everything else, they have to mow around
it and make a special excuse for getting
around it and and that's comes a time
when that is just not reasonable. There
should be an end date if someone wants
to put a brief memorial up on public
land.
>> Thank you for being here this evening.
Anybody else?
Welcome, sir.
>> Good evening, Mr. Mayor and members of
the council. Uh, my name is Steven Love.
I live in Ward 1. I do not support this
ordinance. It appears appears to be
unnecessary government intervention.
At the committee meeting, the
justification for this ordinance was the
inconvenience for city workers who must
mow around the memorial memorials placed
around town. This doesn't seem like a
justification to me and more of an
excuse. These memorials are frequently
small and do not impact the citizens of
Cheyenne other than to allow residents
to mourn their loved ones. Furthermore,
the fees imposed seem unnecessary. Why
should a grieving family forced to be
pay forced to pay a fine in addition to
the removal of the memorial of their
loved ones?
It is my recommendation to the council
that at a minimum an amendment be made
in 87.72.0
0 or 20 C to strike $750. And so it
instead reads, "Any person violating the
provisions of this chapter shall be
subject to a fine not to exceed any in
any costs incurred by the city for
removal of this display and add a cap
for said fees. Thank you. Thanks for
being here this evening. Anyone else?"
Okay, hearing nobody else in the
audience, we'll go and get a
a motion. And I got to make sure I get
this right. Dr. Renie.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. The public service
committee met on this and recommended
that we approve on second reading. So, I
would so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by
Dr. Aldridge.
And I would move to amend by
substitution on that's dated um February
13th.
>> Second.
>> Dr. You want to explain the
>> Sure.
>> Um yes. The substitution what it does is
that it um removes the ad the term
advertising because that is already
covered under city code um in a
different part of our um municipal code.
And it also um changes it to include
public right ofway uh which the one um
we have some in our community that um
are on public right ofway currently. The
one that uh Mrs. Garish spoke about is
currently on a public right of way.
>> All right, we'll go out to the audience
and see if there's any comments on the
substitute before us. Um any comments?
>> Okay, how about from the governing body?
Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I was wondering if
we could get a question answered. First
of all,
>> please ask it. I'll get an answer for
you.
>> Um, have we had complaints from the city
staff about mowing around this memorial
and in this area?
>> I don't know. Would that be Craig and uh
or Jason? Um, Craig,
Mr. Lavoy. Any
any concerns from staff?
>> Uh Craig Lavoy public works. None of
them have really expressed anything
other than it does take a little bit
longer and we don't weed eat so we have
to go long
have to go around it wide.
>> Thank you.
>> Followup.
>> Yes, please. So um I go by that memorial
every day. I go by it on my way to work.
I go by it on my way home from work. I
went by it the day the accident happened
right after it happened actually. Um,
and I remember all the cars that were
stopped to try to help the the uh young
woman, Miss Ms. Martinez, who was hit.
This is this memorial hugs the tree. It
is right up against that tree. There is
a good two feet all the way around
between the edge of the memorial and the
edge of the dirt before it hits the
grass. So unless we're mowing dirt,
which I don't think we are, we're not
even coming close to what is in that
memorial. It's very well taken care of.
Um it's never spread out. It's never a
skew. It's obviously very well taken
care of. When I talked to Ms. Martinez's
sister just a short time ago, she said
that there's a gentleman who comes every
day and makes sure that that's picked
up, it's cleaned up, it's maintained,
and it doesn't produce any kind of a
obstruction for people who are mowing or
any kind of a hazard for people who are
driving by there.
So, um I think that this is we've got no
complaints from the city. We've got a
family who takes care of it. We have one
individual who doesn't like it. And I'm
I'm sorry that that's bothersome from
you for you, but I see absolutely no
reason that this has to be moved. It's
not in anybody's way. It's not causing a
problem. Like I said last time we talked
about this. This is a memorial for that
family who this is their way of keeping
that young woman alive
spiritually, mentally, emotionally. And
I just see absolutely no reason to go
forward with this. So I would ask that
people vote no on this ordinance.
>> This this is a point of order. We're on
the amendment. Correct. Understood.
She's talking about the rightway though,
so I thought it was Germaine.
>> Thank you,
>> Dr. Rainey.
>> Mr. Mayor, I think we should support the
ordinance if it cleans it up a little
bit or not the ordinance, we should
support the amendment. If it cleans a
little bit up, cleans it up a little. If
it gets rid of a redundancy between two
different ordinances um
and and clarifies a little bit, I would
support the amendment. Anyone else in
the governing body? All right. The
amendment is a substitute dated 213. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I. I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed?
>> No.
>> Uh Dr. Emmens is a no. The substitute is
adopted. And we're back on the main
motion. Uh comments from members of the
governing body.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Mayor. I just had a
point of information. Um, probably some
of my colleagues know what's the program
that Y dot does to memorialize with a
with a sign.
>> They uh
>> I'm not sure if anybody here can can
talk to that.
>> Jeff can
>> I I know if uh you what I know about it,
Mr. Moody, is that if somebody dies on a
state highway, um their family can
purchase a uh memorial sign and and
place it in the rideway. I'm not sure
for how long, but uh they have the
ability to do that.
>> And so I
Dr. Aldridge,
>> Mayor Collins through you. Uh first and
foremost, I think that this is a really
sensitive subject and I um I would say
that while we've talked a lot about um
Andrea Martinez's memorial, there
actually is a second memorial on Nation
Way further down. Um, and so it's not
just one memorial. And if and I think
there are definitely lots of ways that
families can memorialize their loved
ones. Um, one is through the traffic
sign program that the Wyoming Department
of Transportation offers and actually
that's at no cost to the family. I did
receive the information on that from um
the police department when I contacted
them who referred me to the sheriff's
office and got information from the
sheriff's office. Um, there is no cost.
it. They allow those signs to be up for
10 years and then if they'd like to have
them replaced, it's $50. Um, but it has
to be written by a family member in
order to initiate that. Um, my largest
concern is that um we have had in in
Ward 3 of these many accidents,
unfortunately, many tragic accidents.
Um, some are memorial some are memorials
that are on College Drive. You've
probably seen those. Those are on a
state highway. So, those are not under
our um purview. We have one that is um
by a shopping center on a shopping
cent's uh turnin by the old sheries. Um
and that's on private property. We've
had uh two motorcyclists killed at
Nation Way and Lincoln Way and that was
on private property where those
memorials were um for a variety of 7 to
10 days. Um, and then we had a young man
that his car flipped and landed in the
McDonald's parking lot and was killed
and that memorial was there for five to
seven days. So, this is looking to put
some consistency on these types of
memorials. There are a lot of memorials
that can be done through our parks
department. I know families have worked
with our parks department to put benches
um on public property or in the parks.
Um, plant trees. There's a variety of
ways that families can memorialize. And
I think we definitely offer those
opportunities. Um, but I do have some
concerns when we talk about and I have
had city staff talk about that they want
to be cautious about mowing around them
and not do any damage. Um, the one that
um, my colleague referred to is really
wellmaintained and kept. Um it is a
little troublesome to think that
somebody's crossing nation way every day
to go out and maintain it. Um because
that's not necessarily a an area with a
crossing area that um people recognize
or would be cognizant that somebody
might be crossing there. I believe the
um traffic speed limit there is is it 45
or 50 miles an hour. So probably not
some place where we want people out in
the middle of the the roadway working.
Um, but I would appreciate um just
having some guidelines and um in our
ordinance that um give families um some
an idea of how to memorialize their love
loved ones um in an appropriate method.
>> Mr. Escoel,
>> thank you. Mr. Mayor, through you the
point that Dr. Rich just made about that
uh memorial. You have to cross two lanes
of traffic that is going at least 40 m
an hour through there. Uh I think it's a
dangerous place to uh either stop your
vehicle along that right away and then
get out and try and uh do something in
the middle of it. Uh, I don't want to
see another accident happen just because
someone is uh trying to go and add
something to a memorial. It's basically
a four-lane highway if you look at it
that way.
>> Other comments from the governing body.
>> Mr. Wolf.
>> Mr. Mayor, thank you very much. Um I
I've kind of struggled with this um and
uh understand uh Councilwoman Emmen's uh
strong and significant comments. Um I I
guess we're not first of all this is an
ordinance of general application. So
we're not enacting an ordinance for one
memorial. Uh, and I appreciate
Councilwoman uh Aldridge uh uh bringing
this a substitute is uh I thought much
improved over the original version. So,
as we vote on this, we should decide
whether or not this is good policy for
the city to adopt. Um and um I guess I
kind of come down that it probably is
good policy. Um so I'll vote uh I'll
vote on this. I do however think that
Mr. Love's comments about the fine are
well taken. Um, and I would ask the city
attorney whether or the sponsor whether
there is any uh reason we have to have a
fine in here.
>> Dr. Aldridge.
Well, I believe that the reason that the
fine is here and and we should note that
it says that a fine not to exceed $750,
which I believe is um gives the if there
were to be a fine issued, it would give
a lot of leniency to whoever was issuing
the fine. But my understanding is that
that is is that the misdemeanor amount?
>> Mr. Brody
>> for consistency.
>> Uh Mr. Mayor, John Brody, city attorney.
Yeah, I mean state statute affords
municipalities um enforcement authority
for ordinances and that is a up to six
months in jail up to a $750 fine or
both. Um so it's uh would be up to the
prosecutor to make a recommendation if
this were to go in front of a court and
then ultimately it'd be up to the
municipal judge to issue a punishment.
Um
in the the years I've been with the
city, I've never seen a fine at $750.
So, um, that doesn't mean it's not
possible, obviously, if it's in the
ordinance, but, um, I think our court is
pretty cognizant of the specifics of
each situation that comes before it.
>> Doesn't the judge typically create a
bond schedule for different offenses
that the officers would write?
>> Yes, for the citation purposes. You're
you're correct, mayor.
>> Uh, Mr. Wolf,
>> thank you, Mr. Birdie. Um, uh, Mayor
through you. Um, just a actually a
question for the sponsor. Um uh what
would what would you think of an
amendment that actually removed the fine
but said that um they'd be subject to
payment of any cost incurred by the city
for removal of display not to exceed
$300?
>> Well, I'm immenable to that. Mayor
Collins for you. Um there are three
sponsors on this um piece of
legislation. Um so I would check with my
co-sponsors as well. My one concern
would be the um difficulty.
One, we struggle sometimes to collect um
fines at all, but it how we would then
the burden of figuring out how much
money it cost to remove that and then
sending out a um setting a fine for
that. I just wonder about the the actual
uh logistics of carrying that out. So, I
would defer to the city attorney and to
the police department to um about their
thoughts on how that would look as far
as a fine goes. I think that there's
might be that might be a challenge to
calculate.
>> So, m Mr. Mayor, if if I may, um I I
think part of the the procedural
mechanism and um the enforcement
authority we have through the municipal
court, it would be helpful to have some
type of fine, just an up to amount
because then we can get them um into the
court. And if there is what is
effectively restitution, right, the cost
for removing that memorial, um the court
would then be able to order that
restitution and there would be a
mechanism for the city to um collect
that that money if it were needed.
>> Mr. Wolf, we're on second reading. we
have a week before committee and then
and another week before the third and
final reading. Might give you and
sponsor some time to work through that
issue and maybe make a recommendation at
the next uh committee meeting that we
could look it on third reading.
>> Uh Mr. Mayor, that's an excellent
suggestion and and and I'm not wedded to
this and and I'm not going to bring the
amendment now. So, thank you uh uh Mr.
Brody for your comments and thank you,
Mayor.
>> Thank you. Any comments? Yes, Dr.
Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I also do want to
just be on the record that we do have an
individual that this ordinance. So, uh,
the f when I talk to the family tonight,
they are against this. So, I just want
to be on the record with that.
>> Thank you,
>> Mayor Collins through you, Dr. I'd like
to be on the record for saying that I
talked to that same family member
initially before we ever brought this
forward and the family and uh two family
members the one that now is against it
and um another family member were in
favor of it. So um I think as this
progresses that it sometimes um support
changes depending upon how it rolls but
um we will definitely look at this this
amend an amendment that was suggested by
Mr. love and we'll um have that ready
for committee on Tuesday if they should
pass.
>> Thank you
>> on Monday.
>> Anyone else?
All right, we're on the main motion as
uh amended. Um all those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed?
>> No.
>> Dr. Rainey and Dr. Emmens are nos. The
ordinance is approved on second reading
as amended.
Next item is number eight, ordinance
second reading, amending the official
zoning map of the city of Cheyenne,
changing the zoning classification for
certain land located north of Prairie
Avenue, east of Powderhouse Road, west
of Rutter, and south of Story Boulevard
from AG Agricultural to NR3 neighborhood
residential highdensity.
>> All right, we have an ordinance before
us tonight that will allow a 54 unit
senior housing development to move
forward. and we'll go out to the
audience if anybody's here to talk about
this zone change. Anybody?
>> Good evening.
>> Uh good evening um Mr. Mayor and council
members. Uh my name is Andrew Schaefer
and I'm uh with Real Estate Equities
Development Company. We are the
developer of the proposed village
cooperative community that this reszone
is is for and we're just excited to be
here tonight and and be working through
the process for the project approvals
and uh hopefully be bringing our
community to the city of Cheyenne uh
very soon. And with that, I'll just if
there are any questions, I'm happy to
answer them.
>> You know, a question was asked uh during
our last meeting about when the plans
were to break ground and um and you
know, maybe a little bit about the the
length of time to uh do the development.
Yes, I'd be happy to to to share that.
Uh, right now our our schedule is to try
to get all of the uh entitlement
approvals uh in the next um few weeks
and we will be finalizing architectural
and engineering plans for the project
this spring and getting them out for for
bid and we work through a process for
project financing and we would hope to
have that all completed and break ground
on the project this fall.
>> Very good. And and I did I hear
something like 16 18 months to build it?
Does that
>> Yeah, we you know it really depends what
time of year we break ground on it and
how how the weather goes, but uh on
average it takes somewhere between 16 to
maybe 19 months at the longest uh to
construct a community like this.
>> Very good. Thank you for being here. Any
questions for the developer?
>> Andrew, thanks. Appreciate it very much.
>> Anybody else that want to speak?
>> All right. Um Dr. Rainey,
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to approve
on second reading and I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Escoel.
>> Comments on the zone change for members
of the governing body.
>> Hearing none. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Those opposed.
>> The ordinance is approved on second
reading. And good luck, Leander.
Number nine, ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne, changing the zoning
classification for land located
southeast of the intersection of South
Kirley Highway and East Asia Lane from
AG Agricultural to BP Business Park.
>> All right, we have u an expanding bison
business park. This is 78 acres to uh be
zoned uh business park from
agricultural. Is there anybody here that
would like to speak to the zone change?
All right. And this would be Dr. Emmens
or Dr. Renie again.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to approve
on second reading and I would so move.
>> Seconded by Mr. Moody.
>> Do we have any comments for members of
the governing body on this zone change?
Hearing none. All those in favor please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
>> All right. The zone change is approved
on second reading.
Number 10, ordinance, second reading,
annexing to the city of Cheyenne,
Wyoming, various tracks of land
completely surrounded by current city
limits situate in western and southern
Cheyenne generally located east of I25,
south of the intersection of Westland
Road and Missile Drive and north of West
and East Allison Road and east of and
adjacent to North College Drive.
>> All right. Before us now, we have an
ordinance to annex the last group of
county pockets which we identify as 100%
surrounded by the city. And we'll open
it up to the public and see if anybody
wants to comment on this item.
Anybody in the public,
>> David, welcome.
>> Welcome. Thank you. Um
David Nicely 200 Walters uh WFresh Farm.
Um
at our last um well first of all thank
you to council people and uh
to the audience and those of who support
us to city staff. Um thank you for being
here. Um thank you to you and on the
council for listening to us and for your
patience with us as we uh try to wrap
our heads around what's happening.
Um at our last council meeting, um close
to the end of our the comment period on
Wresh,
um Councilwoman Emmens, uh asked us to
asked me to amend my initial request
that we not only be kind and respectful,
but that we be trusting. And um I
thought about that and uh I agree with
that. Um, love believes all things,
hopes all things. And so I'm hopeful.
Um, I'm hopeful because as a follower of
Jesus, I know that he majors in taking
lemons that have been thrown on the
floor and stomped on and making
lemonade. And so I still believe that we
can make lemonade as Councilwoman Emmens
asked us to. Um, and I hope we're in the
process of doing that. But it's been a
lot of stomping and a lot of lemon on
the floor and um it's been a lot of
stress. Um but we can be kind
and we can be respectful and we can be
hopeful
um that good things can happen. And so
I'm here tonight um saying that um we're
still hopeful that um should the council
go forward and force us to be in a
relationship that we're not ready for,
we still believe that it could develop
into a great relationship. But I don't
recommend the process of doing that
without kindness and disrespectfully.
Um, and it's hard to trust in that
situation, but we'll trust uh Jesus um
to make lemonade out of the lemons even
if the stomping continues. And thank
you.
>> Thank you for being here again this
evening.
>> Sir, please come forward.
>> It's nice to see you again.
Um, Donald Carrer, Cheyenne, Wyoming.
Thank you, mayor. Thank you, council.
This has been a little bit kind of back
and forth with me. There was one part of
me where I wanted to come up and really
be frustrated with it and I'm trying to
pull it back in. So, I'm just going to
just read this.
Obviously, we're gathered here again
tonight. I'm in support of the Y fresh
farm. We've heard such an overwhelming
come together of the community. And I
want to emphasize that uh as our you
guys as our elected representatives, you
guys are accountable to us, the
constituents.
This farm stand has been an issue for a
few weeks now and the community is
watching. The people are watching.
Um,
we have seen such a constant expressing
in support of this family in the the
farm stand that it's it's both
heartwarming and it's also sad. Um,
the city is pushing for this annexation.
It is perceived negatively by the
public. So far, I haven't heard one
person stand up here and speak um
against the Farmfish family or against
the family.
Um, you know,
no one's f has voiced opposition. Um,
and it does underscore um a
a unity that everybody that has come
together and you guys are constituents
doesn't feel like you guys are listening
to the voices of the people says if I
believe if you claim that you serve the
people interest how do you rationalize
pursuing a c or a course that directly
contradicts the community's desires?
Mayor Collins, your vision for annexing
properties has been well documented.
However, I would say that the approach
seems to disregard the value of
community input. It is essential for our
governing body to prioritize the welfare
of local families and businesses. We
need collaborative solutions, not
divisive ones. The people gathered here
tonight are witness to the support that
this community is has embraced. I would
just respectfully ask and request that
you halt the annexation pro proceedings
and work towards a more and inclusive
solution. And in closing,
I I think that it's to me it's crazy.
You know, I don't know what goes on
behind closed doors with any of you
guys. I don't do your guys' job. But
when I hear a grown man stand up here
professing his faith, which is a bold
act anymore these days, and and beg
that you guys work with him, and I'm not
saying that you guys haven't worked with
them. So, please do not misunderstand
that. But the bottom line is is to the
to the public and to the eye of
everybody else, you guys work for us.
Don't forget that. And if people are
upset at any of these people up here,
remember when it comes to voting time,
don't vote for these same people because
the voices have spoke. I mean, we the
people have said, "Why? You guys might
have all the authority. You guys might
have all the things to do it, but that
doesn't make it right." Thank you.
>> Thank you, Donald.
>> Mr. Love, welcome back.
>> Mr. Mayor, uh, members of the council,
I'm here to support the nicely, um, and
the owners of the southernmost pocket,
our property of pocket 7. I attended the
public services committee meeting and
versed my concerns about this
annexation. I think this annexation
needs to be annih amended to remove the
property in pocket 4 and the
southernmost property of pocket 7 until
an urban farm zoning definition can be
codified and reflected in zoning
regulations with such protections as the
ability to increase the quantity of
livestock, add new species of lives
livestock, clearly stated allocations
for the construction of fences and
agriculture related structures without
the need to file permitting with the
city among other protections. for the
continuation of agricultural use on
these properties. The current AG
designation does not provide adequate
protection for these properties and is
vague. The planning department has made
promises about the ability of the nicely
to draw simple diagrams and the city
will approve them. I do not trust the
government to follow through on promises
or informal formal memorializations of
definitions. One reason given for the
necessity of annexation is fire, police,
and emergency services. However, as
Sheriff Kak stated, the county has an
agreement with the city to provide these
services.
So, to me, there does not seem to be any
reason to annex until an urban farm and
the necessary protections can be enacted
in the zoning regulation.
Furthermore, if the city insists on
annexation of the property in pock
pocket 4, the city could easily, as part
of the upcoming roundabout construction,
install a deceleration lane and tie-ins
to city infrastructure um up to the
easement of the property. This would be
a sign of good faith to the nicely that
there may be that they may be able to
run their farm and business well into
their future and their children's future
without undue financial strain. I
understand Mr. Moody is proposing an
amendment to remove these properties
tonight. Seeing as seeing as no one has
come out in favor of the sanaxation, I
would en encourage you to hear the
voices of so many Cheyenne residents and
vote yes on that amendment. Thank you.
>> Anyone else this evening?
>> How you guys doing today?
>> Good, sir.
>> Yeah. My name is uh Brian Pixley. I'm a
a Wyoming native. I've been here for
over 50 years and uh I totally uh do not
support this annexations. For one, uh uh
my my mom and dad a long time ago got
annexation in the city and they had to
pay for their own water, mines, own
sewer, and everything else. So and and
and where where was you where was you
guys when you guys needed when we needed
us is you know for like the lines and
all that you know we were we're on
wellwater that's why a lot of people in
Cheyenne had the wellwater signs on
their houses you know because they
didn't want to be annexing in the city
you know so basically I I so highly
support these uh uh people that you know
trying to save their farm and all that
stuff you know trying
make a living for themselves, you know.
So, I fully support them. So, thank you
and have a nice day.
>> Thanks for being here.
>> Hello, welcome back.
>> Hi, my name is Richard Nicely. I am the
son of uh David and Tommy Nicely.
And
I would like to just say and I
I write for my classical teacher. So,
but I would like to say a few things
throughout the millennia that we have
walked the globe as a species.
We have always treated each other or one
another with a certain level of respect.
This respect I feel like we have been
wanting from the city
and not been receiving it.
Throughout the dis course of these
discussions and debates our one major
question has or asked is
can we please get a postponement? We are
not we are perfectly willing to change
Caesars. We are perfectly willing to
change our loyalty from the county to
the city if the city is able to is able
and willing to meet our needs as a
family and as a farm.
I have wanted to expand my flock of
sheep. I own three sheep. I was like
eight when I got my first sheep. I have
been wanting to expand my flock of sheep
for a while now.
With this going with this pressing
annexation, it looks like I will not be
able to do so as it will require
increased infrastructure, a stronger
fence which we have not been provided.
Uh past administrations have even
knocked it down. Uh that is not a stain
on the current city administration but
on past but we have not been provided
with a fence and it has been taken away
from us. I want a little flock.
If I am to expand my flock of sheep, uh
that would require a larger barn than I
currently have, which under current city
code then requires
my my my
parents to then get building permits.
And as far I am not an expert,
my mom would probably like to build more
green houses.
That falls under the same problem as the
barn.
And
I pray to current council to put off
this annexation till a later date as all
great things take time. The cathedrals
of Europe for example took half a
millennium to build the pyramid to
build. The pyramids took 20 years of
struggle. This farm has already toiled
for 20. For many councilmen present,
their current situation in government is
that of one based off of 20 years or
more of hard labor in and out of office.
We are not asking for much. We simply
ask why we c we cannot put this
annexation off. And so in conclusion, I
pray I beg to have this annexation put
off till a later date to lay the
keystone for a better Cheyenne and so
that a Cheyenne and so that Cheyenne may
shine as a light in the darkness of
tyranny and of death and of the desolate
situation of man.
>> That is all.
>> Thank you, Richard. Appreciate you being
here again. Your mom's very proud. I can
see it in her face.
All right. Anybody else?
Good evening, sir.
>> Good evening.
>> Bring that microphone up a little bit,
would you? There you go.
>> Good evening, mayor. Uh, city council.
Uh, my name is Micah Sutton, Cheyenne
resident, speaking in favor of postpone
of the annexation of Wresh.
I've been a customer there for some time
now. They have great products. They are
very healthy and have helped me in my
food journey as I have several health
issues related to diet.
and they have been great for my
lifestyle. [snorts]
You'll notice I'm wearing a green safety
vest tonight. Uh this is related to the
misinformation spread in regards to
unsafe firearm practices that endanger
the public according to the Wyoming
Tribune Eagle. This has been refuted by
the sheriff's and county police
departments as well as the city.
The process that if they are annexed is
quoted in
city ordinance 15-1-421
municipal deanexation. I will just read
a small portion of that here. The owners
of all the land to be deanexed either
sign the petition for deanexation or
consent to the deanexation within 120
days after the final passage of the dean
annexation ordinance and before its
effective date. The passage of the
ordinance shall serve as the consent of
the city or town for any land owned by
the city or town within the area to be
deanexed.
That is a lot of land that is in this
parcel. That would require more than
just the nicely. that would require more
uh
ability
than is obviously present here tonight
to present.
This will indefinitely ensure that this
land may or may not be annexed back out
into the county without the state taking
back control, which was also mentioned
in the previous city council meeting.
Please consider the vast outpouring of
public opinion on this matter and thank
you for your time.
>> Thanks sir.
Thank you. Sorry about that. Um hi. My
name is Chelsea McCort. Um I'm in uh
Ward One. Um quick one second point of
order before I begin is if I say we I'm
uh speaking on behalf of Wesh. I've been
working with this so um I know a lot
about the background behind it. Um thank
you guys for allowing us to express our
opinion and thank you to all the hard
city workers and other departments heads
that have worked with us so far. It's
been a lot of work. I know it but we
truly appreciate that. Um why fresh is
very important and valuable to the
community. If you have any questions
just look in the room see all the green
shirts. remember all the comments that
have spoken the last couple meetings. Um
so I don't think I really need to
reiterate that. Um the the simplest hope
that WFresh is is hoping for is firstly
to separate themselves. Uh so that's
parcel 4 and also to separate the other
urban agricultural parcel parcel 7 from
the current annexation so that we're not
holding up any other proceedings. The
ones that don't have a problem, let's
get them annexed if they are fine with
that. Um and then the secondary step
would be to postpone the annexation
until some problems have been resolved.
Um in the public servicey committee
meeting uh Councilman Lebornne wanted us
to demonstrate need of why we need a
postponement. And I hope that I am able
to demonstrate that with the remaining
time. Uh firstly I think it's important
to note that we're not asking for an
indefinite postponement. This is not us
trying to play a game where we're
waiting for years to finally get
annexed. this is something that we just
simply need more time to do. Um, you
know, I I can't imagine truly that it
would take more than 3 months to be able
to get everything done and that's that's
on a high-end estimate is our hope. Um,
I think that a few reasons why there's a
need for annexation. Um, we wer myself
cannot work at the same pace as city
workers as city department heads. were
three people with multiple jobs with
children homeschooling doing all these
things. Um,
and that the emotional, physical, and
uh, mental health of us is suffering.
Um, I've had multiple conversations with
Tommy um, expressing concern about is
this even worth fighting for? Is this is
her dream. This has always been her
dream. And to hear her say that has been
so incredibly discouraging. Um, one
other thing that I think is really
important to note is that um, there's a
discussion about the fence that has been
damaged and we appreciate the city for
jumping on that and being able to to
work on repairing it. It's important
that it be repaired before annexation
because we need to be able to protect
our predators and upon annexation, we're
restricted in what we can and can't use
to remove predators. Um, so going along
with that, uh, Doug Clong uh, sent an
email to the city. Um, and I would like
to read two quick paragraphs from that.
It says, quote, I hope I have some
clarity detailing the next two weeks.
However, that will largely depend on the
weather and contractor's availability.
And then he goes on to also express that
um the engineer for the drainage will
also take time. Uh
literally two weeks takes us to the
March 9th deadline and that's just
getting the stuff figured out. That
isn't the actual work. So that's clear
proof that two weeks is not sufficient
to be able to pass it and still allow
WFresh to operate fully.
Thank you.
All right. Anybody else?
Jennifer, anybody online?
Nope.
>> There are no hands raised.
>> All right. Anybody else? Last call for
anybody in the audience.
>> Okay. We'll uh close the public comment
then and we'll uh ask Dr. Rainey for a
motion.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public ser committee is to approve on
second reading. And I would so move.
>> Mr. Mayor, I would move to postpone. I
need to get a second, please.
>> Second.
>> Awesome.
>> Dr. Aldridge,
>> I would move to postpone.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion to postpone. Um, we'll
go back out to the audience. When we
postpone in the governing body, that
means it just be postponed for two
weeks. Um, I think I know the all
everybody in the green shirt what your
answer would be, but you're welcome to
come up and speak if you'd like.
>> Okay. How about from the governing body?
Collins,
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Um I would encourage my colleagues to
vote for this postponement. Um there was
a list of questions that had been
alluded to during the public services um
committee meeting. Um that p that list
of questions was received by I believe
our director of planning um this week
and it had and I'm trying to remember
exactly but over I think around 140
questions
>> 143
>> 143 questions on it. Um and some of them
were um quite lengthy and some of them
were easily answered but some of them
were going to take some time in addition
to the engineering and the fence issues
as well. Um I know that a twoe
postponement um may not be sufficient.
Um, but there is no limitation to the
number of times this can be postponed.
Um, until we can get I just feel like we
need to be able to get the answers um
from our city staff um and give our city
staff time to get those questions
answered um before we proceed with this
um annexation. So, I would ask my
colleagues to consider postponing this
um for two weeks to at least hopefully
give staff enough time to be able to get
the questions answered.
>> Dr. Reie, did you have a comment?
>> No, Mr. Mayor, since it's on second
reading, we do have the our staff does
have two more weeks to answer questions,
though seems to me if we do have to
postpone it, it makes more sense to do
it at third reading.
>> Anybody else?
>> Dr.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I I just need some
clarifications. So, we got 80 questions
in like Wednesday, I believe. Yes,
ma'am.
>> And then we got 140 questions in Friday
afternoon at almost 3:00.
>> Is that correct,
>> Dr. Em? I think that included the first
80 questions. So, I think it's a total
of 143.
>> Yes. So, we got 80 in on Wednesday and
then we got an additional 60 on Friday.
>> Yes. So um Mr. Mayor follow up. So I
guess my confusion is
around what it is that um
you're needing. Is it the answers to the
questions that is why we need to
postpone
or is there you keep talking I'm sorry
Mr. Mayor. Um, I hear people talking
about getting ready, but I don't
understand the what we're getting ready
for. Is it just for the answers to the
questions or
>> Dr. Aldidge, you made the motion?
>> I believe that uh the twoe postponement
would allow our staff to be able to get
the answers to the 143 questions. That's
why I'm asking for a postponement. uh
recognizing that yes, there is another
two-eek period before reading the third
reading, but I believe that it is going
to um be more involved to get the
answers than possibly two weeks.
I can share with you guys that staff has
been working on these pretty hard and um
I think a first draft of most of those
answers is done and uh and we are
working on uh the ones that came in at
at the last minute. But uh we will have
those questions answered and and to
everybody I think by the time the
committee meeting starts or before the
committee meeting. That's our that's our
goal. Anybody else? Mr. Labour.
[snorts]
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. [clears throat]
I uh
speak in favor of the uh adoption of
this uh ordinance on second reading
and I want to point out that there's
been a lot of
>> we have a point of order. We're on the
postponement for two weeks or is that
where you're at?
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> Okay. I apologize then. Thank you.
[snorts]
>> And uh I believe that one of the reasons
I've just heard in this discussion
was the answering of those 143
questions.
And I don't believe we ought to be
postponing this for that reason.
Uh when I read those questions, one of
them was, are we going to require barn
cats to be leashed on this property?
Um I can answer you that that is not
going to happen. And I think a number of
those questions were pretty similar.
Um there are specific issues here. I
look forward to discussing these issues.
But a postponement
for this purpose
uh in my opinion adds nothing.
We can work through these issues. I've
I'm a member of the the public service
committee. We'll be looking at it. But a
number of these questions and the whole
discussion that has gone on here, we're
not answering these questions. we're not
answering these questions. Well, some of
those questions just are not really
specific to the issues that we're
talking about. So, I speak against uh
postponement for the reason that uh we
go through this and we have gone through
this with a number of other annexations
and work through those issues.
And I think that if they were serious
questions,
um I certainly welcome that opportunity
to learn more about them. But whether
we're going to be requiring barn cats to
be leashed
is uh one of those questions
and I don't think that that's
appropriate. Thank you,
>> Mr. Escoel.
>> Mr. Mayor, do you uh rather than
postpone it, I would prefer that we just
remove parcel 4 and seven from this
annexation.
Anybody else on the postponement?
>> Mr. Wolf. Uh, thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Through you. Um,
[snorts]
what we're faced with here is is a
question as old as government itself,
which is what what obligations does a
government owe to individuals that are
the governed?
Uh this council collectively represents
65,000
people
and we've been asked to be kind and
respectful
through now multiple hearings
of multiple uh
hours of staff time that has been
devoted to this. multiple hours of this
council's time that have been devoted to
this and all of which is time and effort
that could be devoted to the other
65,000
minus two um that we faced are faced
with here. Um, and
well, I'm totally sympathetic to what uh
the Nicely have and to what the public
has found in their uh farm and farm
stand. Uh, we're not taking this land.
We're just putting it into the city. And
does it come with additional
restrictions?
It may. Um but it's um it's not like the
it's not this is not an eminent domain
proceeding. Um and we have questions
that need to be answered. We have time
to do that. And I agree with Dr. Renie
that if we should take this to uh back
to the committee, we should then bring
this back to the uh council. And uh if
at that time the questions aren't
answered then um we this motion would be
appropriate. Thank you
>> Dr. Alders.
>> Mayor Collins through you. Um the reason
another reason that I'm asking for this
postponement is because um I had talked
with my colleague from W three who had
talked about doing uh an amendment to um
remove section for parcels four and
seven from this annexation. I believe
that sets a really bad precedent um to
have an annexation um proposed and all
the work that's been done on it and then
to simply just remove two properties um
from that annexation process. Um so my
hope is that through a um a postponement
that we can get to the point where we
have common ground and can then do this
annexation in uh its entirety.
Anyone else?
All right. Hearing none, the motion is
to postpone. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed?
>> No.
>> You see the hands in the nose.
>> Dr. Rainey, Dr. Emmens, Mr. Wolf,
Mr. Leborn, and myself, Mr. Crave. Uh,
no.
>> The postponement fails
>> and we're back on the main motion.
>> Mr. Mayor, Mr. Moody. Mr. Mayor, I move
to amend by uh sub number 10. And
everybody on council, I gave you a copy
including the email and if I could have
a second, I would explain.
>> Second.
>> Okay,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you.
So, what this does uh me members of the
public and my fellow colleagues is
remove parcel 4 and parcel 7 entirely.
So that way it does give significant
time to define what an urban farm is and
allow for all those questions to be
answered. You know, whatever time it
takes. And again, it will require the
staff to make some necessary conforming
amendments, some more exhibits. That is
why the acreage in this substitute is to
be determined. But all it simply does is
remove these two parcels.
And I'll explain more why we should do
this. Go ahead.
>> Oh, after a public comment.
>> Go ahead.
>> I do think that the public has said that
they don't want this to be annexed. We
keep hearing it from our constituents.
I've had no constituents say they wanted
to be annexed. These two properties,
there is unity around this. I would
definitely encourage my colleagues to
support this.
>> Thank you. All right. I think again I
know what the people in the green shirts
are going to say, but we are welcome to
come up and um and speak if you'd like.
Mr. White,
Mayor Conor, Planning and Development
Department, I just want to make some
clarifying um comments with what this
does and actually have a question as
well. When we say parcel 7, are we
talking about all three parcels that are
involved in parcel 7? because I can tell
you that the two parcels to the north, I
have had contact with one of them and
they don't mind the annexation.
So, I don't believe that we should be
removing all of parcel 7. Additionally,
if this does pass, you also need to make
an amendment to the next item for the
assigned zoning to remove those same
parcels because the assigned zoning also
moves along with the annexation and has
these parcels in there as well.
>> And I'm available for any questions if
there are any. I'm assuming from uh the
look on Mr. Moody's face it's the uh the
AG version of of trackct seven. Thank
you. Anybody else in the audience?
Yes, Jennifer, go ahead.
>> Mr. Sheldon, you can go ahead.
>> Yeah, thank you. Alan Sheldon, W two. Um
I was just actually waiting for this
amendment to speak. Um, I'm in complete
support of uh Mr. Moody's amendment and
I hope that you guys will vote for it.
Thank you.
>> Mr. Love,
>> Mr. Mayor, council members, um, I do
support this amendment. Um,
to, uh, Dr. Alders's point, um, I don't
think we can really set a precedent if
all the other pockets have been annexed.
Um, I I don't think that's really a
concern. Um, I' I'd also like to address
Mr. Wolf's uh [sighs]
analysis that this is only an issue for
just two people. It's not just two
people. You know, um, unfortunately this
room doesn't fit 65,000 people. But I
think, you know, given that no one else
has spoken in support of annexing these
parcels, I think we can safely say that
we speak on behalf of those 65,000
people and we don't want this annexation
to happen. So I again I don't think it
sets a precedent and I think this is the
best path forward.
Thank you.
>> Please nicely. Welcome. Hi, I'm Tommy
Nicely and um I'd like to address a few
issues of um you did talk about barn
cats. There is a leash law in the city.
I don't know if I'm going to be held to
that, but even postponing for two weeks
if I have to now medically alter my barn
cats to have notches in their ears. You
have to give me time to be able to to
fit within city code. Not only that, I
found out last week at a planning
commission meeting that zoning
violations are a criminal offense.
They're not a civil offense and that
really should be dealt with because now
I'm in a position just by continuing to
farm
>> like anything else. I can be a criminal
and it hasn't been done yet, but I don't
want to be the first person to go to
jail because I didn't do a sight plan
because I moved a caterpillar tunnel.
Um, and I think it's very unfair to put
me in that situation.
Um, I don't even think two weeks is
going to be able to address everything.
We have to have our questions answered
and then we need to respond to them and
prepare for them. Um, we still do not
know how we can protect our livestock. I
understand cattle has been in the city
of Cheyenne for many years and cattle
with horns, but we're talking poultry.
Everything likes to eat poultry, stray
dogs, foxes, and sheep that cannot
protect themselves. Um,
I do not know how to protect my
livelihood.
by March 9th. And that is an extreme
fear I have.
Um, and I'm I mean willing. A lot of
those questions should be very easy to
answer and I need to know where they are
in the code. Um, so I can be a
lawabiding citizen. And I do think we
can move forward
in a proactive
way where we can both be a blessing to
each other and I look forward to that.
But I don't think we can do it in two
weeks or four weeks. Um
I'm already a month behind in my
planting because I've been devoting all
this with the questions. Um when we
handed those questions over, we said
it's a rough draft. We're trying to be
thorough. We're trying to be very
careful how we proceed. Um, we're doing
the best we can and I'm very proud of
how far we've done and I am so thankful
for the support of the community and I
that's what keeps me fighting and I I
just continue to appeal to your humanity
that
I just don't think Cheyenne is ready for
encompassing everything why
does and stands for
um
I would ask to just be removed from the
annexation and we just take our time.
There's no need to put the city under a
rush to those that are on salary that
now have extra work. Um I do believe
that's unfair. Also, I think we can move
forward in a very positive, proactive
way. And that's what I'm asking you all
to do. Please,
>> Donald, right?
>> Please come forward.
>> Mr. Mayor, city council, um, I just have
a question. Why what's up with the March
9th deadline? Why then? Why not in a
good act of faith? Again, I'm going to
keep going back to the case in point.
Yeah, there's not 65,000 of us in here,
but I don't see anybody like standing
against these guys. Again, let me just
say this as respectfully as I can. You
guys work for us. That's that's it. No
one in here is sitting here saying,
"Yay, city council." No, we're out here
supporting these guys. And if you guys
are representation of our voice, doesn't
seem like that's real clear.
I mean, I'm not a professional in
civics, but come on now. I don't
understand what the what the big deal is
about a March 9th deadline. I do believe
that you guys have I mean, if I'm being
honest to give you guys some credit, you
guys have worked with people. You guys
are allowing us to talk. You guys are
taking questions. I know emails, phone
calls, etc., etc. But why the rush? I
mean, I I just I don't get it. Sure, you
guys got an agenda. Yes, Mr. Councilman
Wolf pointed out that this is maybe a
distraction from other things. Not our
problem. That doesn't mean that you get
to scapegoat and take the easy path when
you got a family like this and the
public that's coming together. That to
me is very concerning. It's
disheartening because we trust you guys
in in regards if I can just say
something in regards to the questions.
Some of those questions I'm sure to you
guys that you guys see this all the
time. It's probably just this is crazy.
But to a family that hasn't heard the
decorum, the vernacular, they're
probably trying to think to themselves,
we need to answer this as full as it can
because we don't know the pros and the
cons, the consequences, the good, the
right. Why the hurry? That's what I
don't understand. Um, other than that,
you know, it's just
I want to believe in our governing body.
I want to believe that when you guys,
ladies and gentlemen, stand up here that
you guys really are representation of
us. And it I'm sorry that it doesn't it
doesn't seem like it because you've
heard an over I mean it's an
overwhelming response in support of
this. I don't understand what the deal
is. Why is March 9th such a hangup?
Thank you again. Appreciate it.
>> Welcome back.
>> Uh Chelsea McCord again. Um I am also in
favor of this amendment. Um I think it
clearly provides some much needed time
as we've been expressing over the
multitude of these meetings. Um the in
and of itself the the confusion over is
the question do barn cash cats need to
be leashed on the property when the
question was do barn cats apply to leash
law within the city shows specifically
why this sort of thing is important
because there's misunderstanding.
there's miscommunication between us as
the everyday layman city people versus
you guys as the government officials. Um
and and I think that misunderstanding
and oversimplifying some of these issues
again makes it clear that having more
time is necessary to also clarify for
you. Uh Councilwoman Emmens um 68
questions were provided on Wednesday or
was it Tuesday? I can't remember. I was
Wednesday. Thank you. I handed them over
myself and on the top of the paper it
said this is an extremely rough draft
that it would be worked on and then the
143 questions were turnaround. Some of
them are the same questions. Most of
them are revised versions or clarified
versions of those 68 questions. Um so
just so we're aware of what exactly that
is. But those questions have not been
fully answered. Again, they're being
worked on and we certainly appreciate
that. Um, but we also don't think that
all the city workers should see our
issue as an emergency level
situation and need to drop or postpone
their other work or to go out of their
way to kill themselves to be able to
answer the questions for us. We want
them answered obviously and we
appreciate them answered. But simply
adding a little bit more time, whether
that's in removing us through the
annexation or some form of postponement,
allows them that time. it allows all of
us that time. Um, yeah, I I just think
that that in and of the fact that that
there's not a clear direct answer
indicates that there are some systematic
problems with the annexation as it is.
So, thank you
>> and Chelsea, I really appreciate getting
those questions on Wednesday. Gave us a
head start. Um, so we we were able to
make quite a bit of progress uh on those
and we'll continue to work on the rest
of those questions.
>> Anybody else?
Mr. Nicely, welcome back.
>> Um, I would just like to say
what does it speak to us as a culture
that
the we ignore the people in the room
and we go to paint a broad strike of
65,000 people.
the great civilizations, Rome, Carthage,
maybe not Carthage, that's [snorts]
Rome,
>> uh, Sumeriia,
they all fail because their agriculture
in some ways fails.
Sumeriia was a drought. For Rome, their
pathway to the seaures began with the
Senate seizing up smaller property.
If
Cheyenne is to gobble up small holdings
all across it,
and
what I'm saying is Cheyenne can gobble
up small holdings. That might be a good
thing. you're for Cheyenne,
but if you do it in two months,
more things are going to fall through
the cracks.
This is not an emergency.
Uh, as Chelsea pointed out, this is just
asking for questions to be asked. You
don't have to be playing
a game of I'll just say katan where
you're in the resource game early on.
You probably want to be playing a game
of risk.
A year or maybe a two-year postponement
could do a lot. And if we are not put
off of it directly, we live in a culture
of committees.
A small committee that has more time to
do things can do more than a large
government that has a day to answer a
crisis. That is all.
Welcome back, David.
David Nicely 200 Will Tushide.
I may be the only one in this room
that's actually been to court over a
cat.
The judge didn't even ask me how I pled.
Said it would be ridiculous to ask if I
was represented by an attorney. But I'm
back to it again. Um there's a
limitation on the number of cats in the
city.
Um,
our questions are not ridiculous and to
suggest that they are is disrespectful.
Um, it suggests that you're not
listening.
Um, our questions are honest. We're
honest people. Um, we wouldn't have
submitted them if we weren't honest
people. And I would like you to
apologize for implying that we're
dishonest.
That was disrespectful. David, I unkind
>> David, I didn't hear that from anybody
in this thing. I think I've heard of
nothing but respect both ways here
tonight. And um
>> well, I I'd beg to differ. The whole
point of bringing up the
>> it was not a rhetorical question he was
asking. Um so um
>> I'd like to say
>> I've been characterized as begging. I'm
not begging. I'm demanding that you
apologize to my wife for suggesting that
she was dishonest informing her
questions. That was rude, uncalled for,
and unnecessary.
>> David, you've made your point. Thank
you. We're not going to take any more of
that. Okay? We're not going to have an
argument between two people here.
>> I am not arguing. I am simply speaking.
>> And I'm ruling you out of order. Thank
you. We're not going to do that tonight.
>> I am not out of order.
>> Well, I just ruled you out of order.
>> And I'm not accepting that.
>> That's fine. You can sit down and we can
just not accept it. I don't care.
>> Please, sir.
>> Okay. If you have if you want to talk
about the motion before us right now,
which is to remove items four and item
seven from this agenda, I'd love to hear
your comments on that.
>> All right. Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> I'm a in favor of the amendment.
>> [snorts]
>> We need time. The lemons keep being
thrown on the ground and stomped upon.
Three and a half years ago, I opened
this discussion with the city and the
city would have nothing of it. Again and
again, we I asked questions. The calls
would not be returned.
I was asked, we were asked to put
forward a comprehensive list of
questions.
The reason why there's 140 of them is
because we were asked to comprehensively
list them.
The city code is huge. The time required
to do that is huge. I asked for
permission to call the city attorney's
office and ask my questions.
You told me to put together a
comprehensive list of questions and you
would get the answers. That's what we're
doing, Mr. Lelay.
>> Sir, address your questions or your
comments to me, please.
>> Okay. To Mr. labor and through you.
That's what we're doing.
>> And and David, honestly, I did ask you
to do that. You've done it and I've said
thank you here tonight. So, Chesley,
Chelsea, thank you for getting to us
Wednesday. Thank you for the list here.
We will endeavor to do as complete of an
answer as we can and get those to you as
quickly as we can.
>> And again, to Mr. Labor and through you,
that's why there's an issue with cats.
Come on, cats. As you seem to have said,
um that's why they're there.
>> Thank you, David. Appreciate it.
Anybody else?
Okay, we're on the uh the amendment to
remove items four and seven. If there's
nobody else in the audience, we'll go to
the governing body. Um Dr. Rainey,
>> Mr. Mayor, I'd like um I guess I want to
know from from the sponsor of the
amendment. So essentially by
removing parcels four and seven, does
that mean
that they are is it like a motion to
divide the question that they will be
dealt with separately and on their own
or is it just that they're going to be
removed and dropped off and go away and
remain as county islands?
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. They remain
as county islands for the time being so
all these questions can be answered.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mr. Mayor,
>> follow up. Dr.
>> Dr. Ems,
>> thank you, Mr. Mayor. For the sponsor,
do you have any idea how long of time
you would anticipate this process would
take?
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you,
uh, to my colleague from War 2, I do
not, but from what they're saying, it
could take up to six months to a year.
We just don't know because they need to
answer 143 questions as we heard.
>> Mr. Escoel
Mr. Mayor, I would like to divide the
amendment
that is uh appropriate at this time so
that both count or parcel four and seven
could be dealt with separately.
>> Is that an amendment?
>> Um Mr. Mr. Russell, I think that's
exactly what this this does. Um the
motion before us takes number four,
parcel four and the southern part of the
agricultural part of seven and removes
them from the uh ordinance before us um
so that we'd have to deal with them at a
different time.
>> Then I want Mr. Mayor, do you I want to
divide it so they're uh considered
separately.
>> Oh, you want you want to take the two?
Okay. I apologize. I didn't understand
your motion. I apologize. Is there a
second to that?
>> Second.
>> Point of order. I
the motion the motion to divide the
question I don't think is appropriate to
this motion on the floor. I think we
have to dispose of this and then I think
the motion to divide would be
>> and I don't have my copy of Robert's
rules of order here but
>> Dr. What I think has happened is they
made a motion to um remove both four and
seven and he'd like to he'd like to talk
about those individually. So it'd be a
motion
so that one maybe would be removed the
other wouldn't. I don't know the answer
to what the intent is but I think
>> how can you but the mo the Mr. Moody's
amendment is to just drop four and seven
completely. So
>> I think Mr. E might have
>> you can't divide that part of it.
>> You could you can Well, Mr. Brody, do
you have a an opinion? I don't know why
you can't divide. So you would consider
seven separately from four.
>> Uh you from my perspective, Mr. Mayor, I
think it is divisible. Each uh component
of the motion can stand on its own. So I
think it is divisible.
>> Dr. Rainey.
>> I think the main motion was is
divisible. I'm not sure the amendment
is. If if the motion is Mr. So that I
understand then Mr. Moody's amendment is
that
um all the parcels
1, two, three, five, and six
will continue forward through the
annexation process. Parcels four and
seven will stop tonight.
>> Correct.
>> Okay. So,
>> I guess
but I don't know how
I mean, if we're I understand how if
we're enter if we're entertaining all
seven of them, how you can make a motion
to divide out four and seven. We we
debate the one side first and then the
other side second. But essentially, Mr.
Moody's motion is that four and seven
just go away.
>> And what I understand the the motion to
divide would be is we would consider
four, decide if it goes away, consider
seven, decide if it goes away, and then
we be back on the main motion. Well, if
if I I don't think it's in order, but if
you're going to re rule the motion to
divide the question in order, then
that's a non-debatable motion.
>> Correct,
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes.
>> Uh if I could just interject, um 151406
uh speaks to um some of the limitations
on annexation.
>> Yeah.
>> Part of that statute says that a an
annexation issue initiated by a
governing body cannot create a county
pocket.
>> Can I leave a county pocket?
>> Correct. Um this is sort of an
interesting circumstance um that doesn't
fall, you know, I think neatly within
that prohibition. Um but it is something
I think the council needs to be aware of
whether or not by removing these two
pieces of property um that's effectively
going against that prohibition in 15146.
Uh thank you
>> Mr. Brody. I appreciate that. You're
right. We can't do an annexation and
leave a county pocket behind. So either
we have to annex um all of seven or we
but we can't just we can't just leave
part of it. We can't just we can't just
annex part of it and leave part. Right.
So four is island of itself but we seven
would be
>> Mr. Mayor. Yeah it's an issue I just I
want to bring to the council's attention
for your consideration.
>> Thank you.
>> So for a point of information mayor
Collins
>> Dr. Aldridge. Um so for that my
understanding from Councilman Moody was
that his in intention was only to
um pull out um the southern southern
western end of uh parcel 7 which is
basically the fog dairy ranch the old
fog dairy ranch and to leave the two
northern pieces in the annexation. But
what
City Attorney Brody just said is that we
would not be able to do that. We would
have to do all of seven. Um that we
would not be able to do that, which is
another reason, I guess, to divide this
question.
M
>> Mr. Mayor, for clarity, if we divide the
question, we still have the very same
issue, though.
[snorts]
>> I I believe Dr.
if that would allow us then the be a
ability to deal with seven we either
have to annex the whole thing or none of
it um and four being a pocket in its own
we could deal with that separately
if I'm understanding the the motion and
and the concern before you um is that
fair
>> yes mayor and I I I would say that the
the prohibition in in 406 you know it's
not 100% clear as all statutes love to
Um, you know, it's the prohibition on
creating a county pocket. Now, arguably
there's a county pocket already there.
Um, but does the fact that the city
chose to just let a county pocket that
was created remain violate that
prohibition? Um, that's something for
this council to consider. I don't I
don't think the answer is clear.
>> I think we've always taken it, Mr.
Brody, is you can't just annex part of a
county pocket. You either have to annex
a county pocket or you leave it. So,
that's how we've always dealt with it in
the past. Okay. Um, do we have a a
second to Mr. Escoel's motion?
>> Did you?
>> All right. Well, now we're really
getting me confused here. So,
>> All right. We have a motion to consider
um county pocket 7 and county pocket 4
separately. And we're going to go out to
the audience because that's our rule.
>> Oh, you're right. It is. Thank you again
for that. Um, the motion is to divide
those two. All those in favor of
dividing the two, please signify by
saying I. I
>> I
>> those opposed.
>> No.
>> See the hands of the nose, please.
>> Dr. Rainey, Dr. Emmens,
>> Mr. Wolf, Mr. Lebornne, and myself, and
Mr. Caggrave. So, that motion is that
motion fails.
Okay, we're back to the motion to remove
uh pockets four and seven entirely. Uh
actually, I take that back. parcel four
and the AG part of parcel seven
entirely.
Um, Mr. Lelay,
I know this has gone on for quite a
while, but I'm curious if we could get
up on the screen a map of uh
[clears throat]
number seven and the adjacent properties
so that we could be talking about more
than just uh the wild farms. Is that
possible,
>> Mr. White? Do you have that capability
this evening?
>> Should we take a fivem minute break and
let staff take care of that and we can
have a comfort break?
>> I've got the copies here, the original.
We're going to take a fivem minute break
and let staff find those maps and uh
we'll come back at 7:30.
>> I've got the Jennifer, I've got the copy
if you need it.
I'm going to download
That's not going to be.
>> So my understanding correctly that
this would remove
all of items number seven
and number four stands on its own.
So they would be removed and I think
there's the idea here
there will be some continuation of
the zoom I can also go to the other
pages which are zoomed in portions. So
I'll just
the whole I have questions. So,
>> Mr. Wolf.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Councilman Wolf. I need a re I needed to
reverse.
>> All right, ladies and gentlemen. I'm
going to call this meeting back to order
and hopefully we got a few things
accomplished and we had a couple minutes
to to relax and so um we're on the
amendment which removes four and seven
in their entire actually removes four in
entirety and the southern part of seven
and we'll go to Mr. Moody.
>> Uh thank you Mr. Mayor. Just a point of
clarification. So speaking with our city
attorney Mr. Brody and correct me if I'm
wrong it needs to be all or nothing for
number seven. So, not just the southern
a property, but also the other two as
well. So, that was my mistake. And this
is not an official substitute as well.
This is just in draft form. If I have to
make an amendment to include all seven,
I'm willing to do that.
>> Okay. Dr. Ready.
>> Well, Mr. Mayor, that's understanding
that the original um what we have in
front of us is just draft form.
Um, I was hoping that somehow
Councilman, my colleague from W three,
could essentially clarify exactly what
the motion is before us and then
um
and then I at that point then I think I
have questions for our staff and I'd
like to hear from Mr. White when we
>> Mr. Moody, do you want to clarify your
motion then, sir?
>> Uh, yes sir. Um, thank you, Mr. Mayor 3
and my colleague from World War II
pretty much to remove all of number four
and then all of number seven after uh
talking with Mr. Brody
>> and Dr. Aldrich, do you agree with that?
>> I wasn't the second.
>> You were.
>> Okay. Yes, sir.
>> Okay. All right, Dr. Renie.
>> So, Mr. Mayor, if you could could we
have Mr. Wade explain what the impact of
that would be?
Connor, thank you for being here.
>> Mayor, members, council, Connor Way,
Planning Development Department. So,
basically removal of these two. Um,
this would require that I need to
basically amend the entire ordinance.
We'd have to amend the signed zoning
ordinance and I would have to get new
maps created. Um, so I will have to
contact the surveyor to get those done
to so we can have exhibits for the
substitute. Um, removing these parcels.
This is removing them from the
annexation. That doesn't necessarily
mean that we even have to go forward and
annex them at a later date. That's
basically up to council's decision if we
do that or not or they'll have to annex
themselves and pay annexation fees and
application fees and all that. So
that's what this would do is basically
remove them from this annexation
completely.
Um, and again that's basically if this
pocket goes forward, pocket annexation
goes forward, it doesn't mean we have to
do another pocket annexation. If we do
another pocket annexation, that does
require all new notice, all new staff
reports, all new legal notice, basically
going through the whole process again.
>> And Mr. White, how long would it take
and what would it cost to have to have a
survey or redo the maps?
>> Mayor, through you, I don't know exactly
on cost. Um this annexation for these
maps was about 8,500 for the maps and
their time as well as the myars printed
at the end. Um
staff time I mean it's just going
through the normal annexation process.
So we'd be through another three months
of getting through the process because
of legal notice uh mailed notice
planning commission for the assigned
zoning and then the full readings three
readings uh through council. So
>> probably hearing all that. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So about 3 months for the actual
annexation process.
>> Um but that's after obviously I get maps
and those maps get reviewed by staff. So
four
four months roughly.
>> Dr. Ry followup. Did that answer your
question, sir? It
>> did. Thank you, Mayor. Dr. Aldrich.
>> Uh Mayor Collins through you. Um, I'm
just curious about whether we could
uh whether we could add a date certain
on amend this motion to add a date
certain for annexation.
>> Is that
>> Mr. Brody, you're shaking your head? No.
>> No.
>> I'm thinking about it, but
>> I I I don't really see a me
[clears throat] excuse me, John Brody,
city attorney. I really don't see a
mechanism to do that through an
ordinance that isn't speaking to those
parcels if they're completely removed
from the ordinance.
I I just think there's a bit of a
disconnect.
>> Would I mean, are you
>> Dr. Aldridge,
>> would we if we if we rejected this
amendment so that we did not remove the
parcels from this process? Could we
amend this ordinance then to delay with
the date certain these these two
parcels?
>> So like divide and then give them a
separate date for annexation.
>> Mr. Mayor, I I I would certainly
appreciate um planning's input, but from
a technical perspective, I think we
could create a new section in the
ordinance that just applies to these two
uh particular parcels and then have a
different effective date um for that
particular section as far as annexation.
The the complication comes uh I think
with zoning um then that would kind of
complicate that or
>> Mr. Bro, we'd be voting to annex them at
the on March 9th. They just would not
become effective until a different day.
Right. So, it doesn't change the fact
that we're voting. It just would it
would just change the date that it would
become effective.
>> It would delay the date that they come
into the city and then the zoning
ordinance would have to have conforming
amendments to somehow uh
>> Mr. I can see the the wheels turning.
Sir,
>> Mr. Mayor, through you that may be
possible. I do know that there is a
section in the ordinance that basically
says annexation is effect is basically
in effect upon approval and publication.
Um, so I guess if we did add there, I
mean, again, I'd have to work with the
city attorney. Um, but we may be able to
add a section in there that would be
spec specific to those those parcels.
>> Mr. Bloom, you have some wisdom for us.
>> Mayor, members of council, as Connor was
alluding to, yes, you could change how
it's effective. You could have different
sections effective at different times.
That would be something we would have to
work with through the city attorney as
to how that would work.
>> But it would still be, let's say we did
this on March 9th, the the first group
would all be annexed upon publication.
The second group would be a date certain
later on, but would still be annexed. It
just would delay the effectiveness of
that. Is that what you're saying,
>> Mayor, members of council, that is
correct.
>> Okay.
>> So, Mayor Collins, with are we on
comment? Sorry.
>> Um, we are. Um, with that in mind, I
would encourage my colleagues to vote no
on this amendment to um withdraw
sections four and and seven, which now
we know we can't really do seven um
because of the agricultural piece. So,
um without doing all of it, I would
encourage you to vote no so that we
would be able to go ahead and pass this
annexation as it moves forward. And then
we could um
amend it to have a date certain um one
year from March 9th. So March 9th of
2027. Uh that would give us time to do
the things that have been asked for by
um the individuals codifying the urban
farm um information and getting all the
questions answered and having them time
to work towards uh that process.
>> And Dr. Alger, are you thinking we would
do that at the next committee meeting?
we'd have some time to work through
those issues.
>> Yes. But I would encourage us to vote no
tonight because otherwise we won't be
able to it'll be too late. Right,
>> Mr. Escoel?
>> Oh, I was just going to say uh Mr. Mayor
through you. That was why I made the
motion to divide. Uh, of course, any of
you that were on the prevailing side
could make the motion to reconsider.
>> Dr. Emmens have a motion
to reconsider.
Dr. Emtts.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. So, um I think
these comments are where we're talking
about. Now, I'm getting really confused,
but
>> we're on the amendment to remove four
and seven in its entirety. So my concern
with removing seven is that then we have
basically
neglected our responsibility to not
create a county pocket because then
there's going to be a county pocket. And
while we may not be directly I mean
there was already a county pocket. So
there's the potential that a court could
come back and say there already was a
county pocket. So, it's not a big deal.
However, they could also come back and
say, "You had the chance to correct this
issue and you just you've determined
that you did not want to correct the
issue."
>> Dr. Emmens, the motion is to to uh
remove the full right the full pocket.
>> But I'm I'm concerned that if we take
that pocket out,
we have created another pocket. No,
we're we're talking about taking the
whole yellow piece, not just half of it,
>> right?
>> I guess I don't understand the Okay.
>> Okay. There's a legal argument in there.
>> Yes, ma'am. I think I heard it.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Mr. Wolf.
Uh, thank you, Mr. Mayor. Uh, through
you. Um,
I
I think we should move ahead. Uh, Mr.
mayor have a vote on
this uh uh substitute that's in front of
us. Um decide whether it has enough
support. If it does, then we'll um
address the other issues. But I mean, my
fear about this is that 3 months from
now, 6 months from now, a year from now,
we'll still be here and all of you will
still be here and we'll all have a room
full of people with green shirts on it.
Then, uh, we need to, as a council and
as a staff,
uh, and as a city attorney, we need to
bring this to closure. Uh the way to do
that, it seems to me, is to defeat this
motion, keep this on schedule, and then
um have the committee take up uh
Councilwoman Aldridge's suggestion if
that has support. Um I'd also like to
say um that we've heard from everybody
who has come up here who says there's
nobody here speaking in favor of the
annexation. Well, that's not true. And
that's not even the way this works. The
people speaking in favor of this
annexation are all the people in the
city of Cheyenne who have supported
your signature
undertaking, Mr. Mayor, members of the
council now for three and a half years.
So, uh I think we in fact do have a lot
of support. uh and we should go move
forward with our processes, defeat this
motion and then see in two weeks where
we are with it and uh decide at that
point.
>> Thank you, Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you, thank
everybody for your public comment.
The public does not support this
annexation. They have said it over and
over and over and over again. We need to
listen to our constituents.
This is why one of the reasons I ran
because I was in that and I was getting
frustrated and I said I need to take a
stand.
They don't want it annexed. I have heard
no constituents from all political
perspectives
have said no, don't annex them.
I don't see the problem with keeping
them out. Other property owners there,
they do want to be annexed. Fine. Four
and seven have said no. If we want our
constituents to trust us,
please vote I on this.
That's all I have. Thank you,
>> Dr.
>> Mr. Mr. Mayor. Through you, seven has
not said no. One part of seven has said
no. Not all three parts.
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes, Mr. Leborn. [clears throat]
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I speak in
opposition to this motion or this
amendment. Um removing this uh
part this [clears throat] parcel that
really is the point of discussion here
which is uh the farm fresh area
um has implications for uh the other
parcel as has been expressed here. And I
I do appreciate the time, Mr. mayor to
put the map up since I hope that
clarifies some of this to some of the
audience. But
to terminate this process
means those questions aren't going to be
answered.
That we're not going to be able to
clarify what an urban farm is if there
was another application. if the I and I
I look forward to speaking to this if we
can uh defeat this amendment and then
get back to the main motion because
there's a lot of considerations here uh
that I'd like to discuss. But I do speak
against this uh for [snorts] the very
reason that we've gone through this
process
and we're we should continue and see the
process through. If at the
next council meeting there's sufficient
uh votes to terminate the uh this
annexation, so be it. That would be
after we've had the opportunity to
thorough thoroughly review the whole
situation, the specific comments and
what might happen to other properties
that might want to uh maybe not do
something of this magnitude, but um be
able to
uh operate
uh in the city with agricultural
purpose. So, I believe we should turn
this down. Thank you, Dr. Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins, for you. Um, I would
encourage my colleagues to vote no
because I do believe that we can find
common ground. Um, and when I spoke with
um, Mr. Nicely, it the opposition wasn't
necessarily to annexation at all. It was
to being able to get these questions
answered, getting the urban farm
definition codified, um, finding that
common ground. Um when I heard um the
fam the couple speak um from the I'm
always confused whether it's the western
side or the southern side of parcel 7,
but the agricultural zone side of seven.
Um they weren't necessarily opposed
either if they could continue to do the
things that they had planned to do with
that property when they purchased it
with their horses and um their business.
So I don't think we've invested a lot of
time and money and you've invested a lot
of time and money coming and speaking
with us about this. I don't think it's
time to throw the baby out with the
bathwater yet. I think we work on this
for two more weeks or till next u
committee meeting and we look at giving
a date certain that would allow a
different um enactment time for this um
th those two properties to give them
plenty of time to be able to get the
questions answered, get everything
cottified, and to be able to um look at
how they could continue to grow their
businesses um without uh wasting
taxpayers fair money and the time and
energy of staff to on all of the other
parcels that were we haven't heard from
um one one two three five and six. So I
would in for that reason I will be a no
vote on this tonight. Not because I'm
not supporting um the uh
urban farming initiative and wife farm
and our um constituents over at the old
fog dairy. because I believe that this
process we still have time to correct
and make this work for everybody
involved.
>> All right, we have a motion to
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes,
>> I'm sorry. Councilman Craves had his
hand raised.
>> Mr. Crave, sorry you're not feeling
well.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I I appreciate
that. Um I'm happy Mr. uh Councilman
Lebornne has had a chance to be heard.
uh when we left when you uh postpone
when you stopped the meeting
um it was because he asked for the maps
to go up and we've had all this
conversation and we finally got around
to answering his questions.
Um
I am in opposition to this. Um I I don't
understand how it would benefit anyone
um the nicely or anyone else. And uh
anyway,
with that said, I would call a question.
>> Is there any is there any other comments
on the uh
>> any other comments from the governing
body?
All right, we have a motion to remove
four and seven in their entirety. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed?
>> No.
>> May see the hands and the nose. Mr.
Crave, Dr. Dr. Rainey, Dr. Emmens, Mr.
Wolf, Mr. Leborn, Dr. Aldridge, and Mr.
White. That fails.
All right, we're back on the main
motion.
>> Mr. Mayor, Mr. Escoel,
I would just like to say annexation
really isn't a four-letter word. It's
not a bad word. There's been a lot of
successes with annexations, especially
in W 3. You just have to drive around
and look at places that were just weeds
uh blighted properties that are now
flourishing businesses. We've created a
lot of economic development and a lot of
jobs in W three by annexation of uh
county pockets. Uh so
uh this is different though. uh we have
not ever dealt with a farm inside the
city limits and uh I'm going to continue
to allow uh them to have more time to
get all their questions answered and
when they're comfortable with going
forward then I'll be comfortable with
them going forward.
>> Mr. Leborn.
>> Thank you Mr. Mayor.
Well, this is a very sustained and
controversial
annexation
and uh
I really doubt that anyone here uh on
the council or the public or watching at
home uh wants to hear me talk about my
emotions
and my feelings because I've got some.
But I do want to speak to the motion,
Mr. mayor by pointing out that the
decision process that I in in my
experience in mind
is one that has touched on a number of
issues that have been uh discussed and
raised both at this at this these
meetings and in committee. Um, I'm
absolutely
appalled at the uh strangulation of uh
small farms and ranches locally,
nationally. I don't think it's it's
really a very destructive process that
has uh done a lot of harm. I think that
the corporate takeover of groceries and
uh of these products is something that
uh is very harmful uh very very harmful.
But I would point out that in all the
other annexations that we've taken on,
there have been issues
and they've been worked through
and has been pointed just pointed out a
little bit ago that
there are redevelopment. [clears throat]
There is opportunity
and Mr. Mayor, I think that it would be
a big disservice
to all the parcels that we've worked on
for the past three and a half years if
we found that this one situation
justified
uh a unique process.
uh that process is one that uh many many
parcels have gone through and I I don't
doubt that there are probably some other
parcels and I'm very familiar with uh
these areas in this whole process going
back many years who might want to uh do
something not entirely dissimilar from
what uh these individuals want. I mean
there's the not a lot of big spaces but
there is and I want to point out that um
when we get into this um we do allow
individuals to continue their process.
So it really is critical that we follow
through and continue this to the end. um
going back and starting over is just
really not uh in the best interest of
all the people that went through this
process. many many uh north east now
we're out to the south um they they went
through this process and I can assure
you I don't know who else is getting
contacted but I certainly am by people
who are saying hey wait a minute
you're going to change the process for
this particular situation
what about the process I went through
what about that there is a question of
equal treatment here and therefore I
speak in favor of attempting
to answer those questions to work on
this and I believe uh certainly the uh
there is the question of how we would
codify this in the code and I think I
think we should try I I be glad to uh
see what others could do to have an
urban farm and it's certainly this
issue's come up so uh I speak in favor
of passage tonight. I think that it only
makes sense to follow through on what
we've done. And I would point out that
uh and and this basically would be in
ward one, which is my ward. Um I listen
to constituents.
I try to listen to all constituents and
make a balanced opinion. I don't listen
to some constituents. And certainly I
think the point that was raised here is
that uh you haven't had a lot of people
come down and in fact I don't believe
there's been anybody that's come and
testified that they want to see this
annexation but overwhelmingly
they approved this process when they
when they were annexed into the city
through this effort which will bring is
bringing now and will bring benefits
into the future. So, uh, I urge the
council to move ahead and continue this
effort. Dropping it now would not, uh,
not really be beneficial in any way and
would not answer the questions of how
and why, uh, an urban farm could work in
our city. Thank you,
>> Mr. White.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um
I I think this situation is unique in
that we are talking about an actual
working farm. So that makes it different
from all the other annexations that
we've done over the past three and a
half to four years. I had hoped and
earlier I supported the postponement.
Um, I'd hoped that we could postpone
this for a period of time because to me,
getting some clarification
of
an urban what an urban farm looks like
within city limits I think is kind of
the lynch pin for me. We've never come
across this before. We don't
we we we don't have any type of
classification for it. I'm going to
support moving this forward tonight
because I think we need to keep move we
do need to keep moving forward. But I
also think that we seriously should
consider whether it be at uh public
service or the next meeting of the
governing body when it comes up for
third reading postponing again until our
staff is able to get uh the
clarification that's needed on what an
urban farm looks like. um haven't had
time to do that. I don't think that that
can be done in the next one to two
months. Um but for me that's very
important. Um however, I will be
supporting it moving it forward tonight.
>> Dr. Alders,
>> Mayor Collins, through you. I will be
voting uh to support this tonight, but
only because I'm voting to support the
process and because um I'm hopeful that
we're going to be able to add a date
certain that would allow plenty of time
to um get the questions answered to get
the cotification done of urban farming
and to make sure that um we are doing
this uh mindfully and thoughtfully um
and and setting the really the precedent
for future urban farms that may want to
open and within our community. I think
it's a a worthy and noble cause to have
these urban farms and um obviously well
utilized and supported by the community
and I want to um make sure that we lay
that foundation for future farms to come
and the only way to have that continue
to happen is to have this process
continue to work forward. So, for that
reason, I'll I'll be a yes vote tonight
um with looking forward to being able to
allow a date certain on these two
properties.
>> All right. Anybody else from the
governing body?
>> Yes, Jennifer.
>> Mr. Crave.
>> Mr. Crave. Welcome,
>> Mr. Mayor. Thank you.
Through this process, I've been pretty
quiet. I've been listening.
Um there are unique circumstances here.
Uh but I think it's it's circumstances
we can deal with.
Um
the nice are looking for asurances for
guarantees.
We all look for those as much as we
possibly can. Business loves
knowing what the rules are. Just tell us
the rules and we'll make it work.
Americans are great at that, probably
better than most.
I truly believe through this process
that they have more assurances,
I don't know about guarantees, but more
asurances
than they currently have in the county
setting.
prior to this entire process. They were
a member of the county operating,
but I don't think the county is the same
county as we might have known 10 or 12
or 15 years ago. They're much they have
they have building codes. They have all
kinds of um in entities similar to the
city.
Whether the Nicely's
understand it or not, they are now very
visible.
Do they comply with all of the county
codes? That would be a question for the
commissioners. I don't know. I mean, I I
truly don't know.
So, as you walk out tonight, I I think
it's interesting that through this
process,
uh, the Nicely may have more asurances
for their future.
than they did when this process started.
So, I'm going to I'm going to vote to
move this forward. We still have time if
something major changes.
Um I think this is
a win for the community. We've been
working on these things for a long time
and if we need to make adjustments in
the next period of time, I I believe we
can. Thank you.
>> Okay, we're on the uh ordinance on
second reading. Are there any last
minute comments?
All right.
All those in favor of the ordinance on
second reading, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed?
>> No.
>> The ordinance is approved on second
reading with Mr. Escoel and Mr. Moody
voting no.
>> [clears throat]
>> Number 11, ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne, establishing the
zoning classifications of AG,
agricultural, MR, medium density
residential, CB, community business, and
LI, light industrial, for land annex to
the city of Cheyenne. Generally located
east of I25, south of the intersection
of Wesland Road and Missile Drive, north
of West and East Allison Road, and east
of and adjacent to North College Drive.
All right. So, with the annexation of uh
property into the city, we have to give
it a city zone, and that's what this
ordinance does. Um, we try to look at
what the underlying um zones are in the
in the county, what the purposes uh that
the properties used. Our staff goes
through that and then they recommend
these what we call establishing of a
zone. And we'll go out to the audience
to see if anybody has any comments on
the establishment of the zones as
presented.
Okay, Dr. Renie.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to approve
on second reading, and I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Dr. Aldridge.
All right. Comments from members of the
governing body on the zoning.
>> All right. Hearing none. All those in
favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Those opposed. The zoning is approved
on second reading.
>> Number 12, ordinance first reading,
repealing and replacing ordinance number
4603 specifying the monthly storm water
runoff management system user fee in
accordance with section 13.32.050
of the municipal code of the city of
Cheyenne, Wyoming, and providing a
revised effective date.
>> All right, we'll assign this item to the
finance committee. Next item is number
14 on page three. Resolution authorizing
the mayor and city clerk to sign a final
plat for village cooperative city of
Cheyenne, Larby County, Wyoming, located
north of Prairie Avenue, east of
Powderhouse Road, west of Rutter and
south of Story Boulevard.
>> All right, this item was on the consent
agenda, but um the zoning is was on
second reading today and this plat would
have been finalized and so was just out
of order by uh by two weeks. So, um,
what I'd ask the city council to do
would be to postpone this for two weeks
so we can catch it back up, but I'll go
out to the audience first to see if
anybody wants to talk about the, uh,
final plat for village co-ops.
I hear none. Uh, Dr. Renie,
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to adopt
with staff recommendations, and I would
so move.
>> Second,
>> seconded by Mr. Wolf,
>> Mr. Mayor,
>> Mr. Rainey, Dr. There any
>> I would move to postpone until March
9th, 2020,
2026 meeting of the governing body.
>> Second by Mr. Wolf.
>> Second.
>> Anybody in the audience want to speak to
a postponement?
How about from the governing body?
>> All right, hearing none. All those in
favor of a twoe postponement, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. I.
>> Opposed. The postponement is approved.
Number [clears throat] 19A, professional
services agreement between the city of
Cheyenne and TDSI for professional
design services for the repurposing of
the historic pump house.
>> All right. We have a plan to uh um make
the pump house the the home for our
clean and safe program, which means we
would do an adaptive reuse of that
building. We'd restore the south, the
west, and the north edges or uh faces of
that building. uh the roof and all of
that, but the eastern side of it would
have some garage doors that would allow
our team to be able to put their
equipment in and out of that building.
And so, we'll go out to the audience and
see if anybody has any comments on the
professional services agreement to to do
the design work for that.
You sat through that whole meeting. I
appreciate you being here.
>> Thank you, Mayor. Can you hear me?
>> Yeah. Lift that microphone.
>> Can you hear me?
>> Yeah.
>> No.
>> No. Well,
>> should I go to the other one?
>> Sure.
>> Please.
>> Testing.
>> Let's go to the other one.
>> Thanks, Miss Cal. Yeah, it was working.
I don't know.
>> Testing
>> much better.
>> Good evening, mayor and city council.
Marian Callais uh historic Cheyenne
Incorporated vice president.
[clears throat] On behalf of HCI, I
would like to extend my support to the
efforts of Mr. Sanchez and the
Department of Recreation and Events to
rehabilitate and repurpose the pump
house. Seizing upon this opportunity
will solve many problems. Number one, it
will save the pump house from further
talks of demolition. To lose this vital
link to our pioneer heritage would be a
profound cultural loss to our community.
The many winters of abandonment has left
this structure vulnerable and the
urgency to find a solution for its reuse
is acute.
Number two, Mr. Sanchez and his clean
and safe team will finally have a
consolidated space to store their
equipment as well as have a place to use
the restroom, eat their lunch, and
conduct a meeting. This crew works very
hard to keep our downtown looking
beautiful, and they deserve a dignified
space in which to conduct their
business.
Number three, the greenway. Restoring
integrity to the pump house will have
the adjacent benefit of opening up a
proper path that would finally connect
bikers and walkers safely to downtown.
Currently, the greenway path dead ends
at Ames Avenue, forcing bikers and
walkers to navigate Lincolnway in order
to reach downtown. Number four, the
wetlands. This land was developed back
in 2012 for the Capitol Basin Drainage
Project as a means of naturally cleaning
storm water, and it's currently fenced
off. Um, this land has the potential to
be another great outdoor space for
public enjoyment within this city. Train
enthusiasts could have a park-like
environment from which to view the
trains because as of right now, they are
relegated to the parking lot at Benton
15th Street. In addition, this wetlands
area also just so happens to be the land
upon which the original tent city of
Cheyenne was born. Proper care and
maintenance of this land would be a
memorial to the courage, the vision, and
the character of those who founded this
great city. I cannot think of a better
department to have boots on the ground
on this land than the recreation and
events department led by Mr. Sanchez. In
conclusion, rehabilitating the pump
house will not only provide the clean
and safe team with a home base, it will
help connect the greenway, help restore
the wetlands, and potentially create a
new park space. and most importantly
save this historic structure from
continued deterioration.
There was simply no way that an external
investor was going to solve this
problem. The answer to the pump house
could only have come from within the
city itself. In its efforts to find a
solution, the city has conducted work
sessions, put it up for sale, and
allowed historic preservation groups to
host an open house so that the public
had the opportunity to weigh in on the
matter. With overwhelming support, the
public made it clear that it wants to
see this building continue into the
future. The time is now, the opportunity
is here, and we have a very good
solution. Thank you.
Thanks, man, for sitting through our
meeting. Anybody else?
>> You're welcome.
>> All right. Seeing none, Mr. Escoel.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to approve an
amount not to ex exceed $198,93.
And I so move
>> second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White.
>> I know we have a substitute. Is somebody
going to introduce that?
>> Yes. Go ahead, Mr. Wolf. Um thank you
Mr. Mayor through you. Um we do have a
substitute uh in this matter 19A. Um
as and I I support this contract. I
support the work. Um this substitute uh
is just to the scope of services. Um and
um it arose from um
I reviewed the contract and the scope of
services uh in preparing for uh the uh
finance committee meeting. Um I talked
to Mr. uh Director Sanchez. U I went out
with Mr. labor uh a week ago and took a
whole set of photographs
um and um and then um met with um uh
director Sanchez and Mr. Leborn and uh
Miss Callas and Miss Stanfield at 7 a.m.
on Tuesday.
>> Point, Mr. Mayor, I think it requires a
second. I'll be happy to second.
All
right, Mr. Moody, thank you for the
second. Go ahead, Mr. Wolf.
>> Thank you. Um, Mr. Mayor, again through
you. Um, anyway, the the upshot was that
um I uh spent time basically rewriting
the scope of work uh so that uh it
incorporates all of the original uh uh
discussion uh from the consultant's
scope of work. Um, but it adds in all
the photographs so that somebody reading
this wouldn't actually understand what
it is we're talking about, what parts of
the building we're talking about,
because some parts are going to be
demolished, other parts may be
rehabilitated uh and reused, although
they also may be replaced. Um, and it
also uh addresses uh issues that weren't
in the original scope of work uh
including uh questions of access,
fencing, and landscaping. Um all of
which I think are critical to um the
future of this building. Um and all of
which um I believe uh uh will be within
the scope of work or within u extended
uh contracts uh uh as a result of our
relationship with the consultant. And we
should understand that that this
consulting firm uh worked on this
building previously
uh during the um the time period when
there was discussion about uh housing
the chamber of commerce there. So
they're quite familiar uh with the
building and the surrounding property.
And so I would ask um the uh council to
approve um the uh substitute which is
dated
uh on the 20th of uh 2026 February 20th
26. Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
>> Thank you. We'll go out to the audience.
So this u as Mr. Wolf said, um, this
takes exhibit B and just adds some
context to the scope of work, which I
think is much more, um, um, descriptive
of what we're trying to accomplish. Is
there anybody in the audience want to
speak to the substitute?
You can't talk to us. You resigned.
Welcome back. It's so good to see you.
>> Thank you. Very, very good to be here.
Milward Simpson, 3102 Spruce Court. Um,
uh, it's it's pretty clear to me that
this substitute is a good one. is a
positive one. Um it doesn't
substantially
um change the ultimate outcome which uh
the historic preservation community
clearly supports. Appreciate Councilman
Wolf's uh efforts and interest and
outreach. And so uh speaking for myself,
I support this substitute.
>> It's really good to see you. Thanks for
being here.
Anyone else in the audience?
How about for the governing body?
>> Dr. Rainey.
>> Mr. Mr. Mayor, I just want to confirm
that
um TDSI with the change of scope of work
that TDSI's had a chance to look at this
and they're okay with the changes. Mr.
Buyers,
thank you for being here.
>> Mayor, City Council, Randy Buyers with
TDSI. Um through you, Mayor, to Dr.
Ren's question. Um, we were able to uh
work with uh Councilman Wolf's uh
comments and questions uh able to
formulate those into the responses that
you see that are appended to the
original contract. Um his questions
really did serve as an opportunity to
illuminate
um not necessarily to change but to
illuminate what was going to be done.
and um I appreciate his and and
Councilman Leborn's efforts. Um we are
in agreement. Those are you see our
letter appended to the back of the
contract at this time. So
>> Randy, thanks for being here.
>> Followup, Dr. Randy.
>> Yeah, Mr. Mayor, I I'll be brief on
this. Um, Miss Callus said pretty much
everything I wanted to say, and that
was, um, I appreciate the fact that you
and [snorts]
um, Director Sanchez came up with a way
to
take care of their needs and save this
building. And at a much lesser, I mean,
we would have had to find some place for
for clean and safe equipment and an
office for them. And it actually this
option is
is a great option because it saves a
building that we're all concerned about,
restores it to its original status
pretty much, and is actually less
expensive than any other alternatives we
had out there for finding a home for
clean and safe. So, I just wanted to
thank the both of you for coming up with
such a great solution.
>> Thank you.
>> Anybody else in the governing body?
>> All right, we have a substitute before
us. All those in favor, please signify
by saying I.
>> I. I. And
>> those opposed, the substitute it is
adopted. We're back on the main motion.
Last minute comments. [clears throat]
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes, Mr. Leborn.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um, speaking as
the council designated champion of the
pump house. Um, I can't um [snorts]
express enough the difference that this
is going to make. And I I appreciate
what uh
Miss Callas said because she talked
about the entire project. There is much
more to this than just this building.
This is a key essential part of the West
Edge. It is uh it that really deals with
many other uh older buildings and their
and their reuse and that's already
happening as we all know. So, uh,
that's, uh, pretty significant. I'm
really, uh, pleased that this is going
to be the responsibility of, uh,
community recreations and events, which
of course is the parks department, and I
think that the landscaping and the and
the pond and the greenway connection are
in good hands with this. So, this is
really a pretty special occasion for
many of us. And uh I think that uh with
that specificity in this uh substitute,
it really is um something that I hope
the community will understand. And I now
that the fence has been removed, it's
much more visible.
And when you look at the pictures here
that are included,
uh this is major major historic building
rehabilitation.
This is taking something that uh really
many people believe should be demolished
and it's going to turn into something
that is an addition to uh the the
greenway to the water quality to the
community in that area and I think that
it's going to lead to uh some
significant redevelopment. So, um
over the years, many of us have uh
been frustrated and um
seen too many historic buildings go
down. Uh so, this is a
really big big step that makes up in at
least to in my mind for a lot of
mistakes that got made. And more than
anything else, this shows that the
community and the historic preservation
board and the other entities that are
involved here.
We need to be lead by example.
And this example that we're making here
tonight is a amazing example that is
going to encourage others uh in private
properties to take another look to think
about it. And I can think of some other
projects that are happening on 15th
Street and are going to happen on the uh
corridor
that are going to benefit from this
because what we're saying seeing here
tonight and of course this is just the
design. We're going to have to uh fund
the actual construction but we're saying
that historic preservation really
matters to us. And I especially look
forward to the Alliance for Historic
Wyoming spreading the word of what the
capital city is capable of. So, uh,
thanks to everyone. Uh thanks to uh the
people that worked on the substitute and
uh I think we're going to pass this
tonight and really really make a big
difference in a way that uh
is going to be eventually quite
noticeable and approved by the community
at large. Thank you,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you, [clears throat] Mr. Mayor.
Through you and uh yes, I will uh I am
supportive of this again. It's good also
for our cleanest safe crew to have a
central location will be a lot easier in
the long run will save money especially
on fuel and also uh making sure all the
equipment is there in working order.
Thank you Mr. Mayor.
>> Mr. Wolf.
>> Uh Mr. Mayor, thank you very much uh
through you. Um just briefly I wanted to
thank you and your staff, Mr. Mayor. Uh
I want to particularly thank Director
Sanchez um for his work on this um and
thank Mr. buyers and TDSI
uh and Mr. Brody and David Hopkinson and
his office who um uh reviewed this and
um I think it's a u it's a good
solution. Um I would encourage anybody
who's interested in this to look at this
contract, look at the pictures, get a
real feel for it. Uh and to uh Marin and
Megan um thank you for all of your time
and effort in coming to a early morning
meeting and uh and um and then of course
to Councilman Leburn who uh dragged me
down there on uh Monday morning uh and
um and then we we got it done. So thank
you.
>> Any other comments?
All right. Before we vote, I just want
to say, you know, we had a really long
almost like their wife um discussion
about the um pump house a number of
months ago and director Sanchez came up
to me afterwards and said, "I think I've
got a way to you can kill two birds with
one stone," which is a home for his uh
clean and safe department and taking
care of his employees, which I really
appreciate his uh thinking about his
employees and making sure they're taken
care of, but also, you know, finding a
way to save this building and to uh um
coales around that. And um I know I do
agree with uh our our former chairman of
our historic preservation board who
said, you know, I think it was him that
we're just maybe it was Marin said that
we're just probably never going to be
able to find somebody who's going to put
$4 million into a building worth $1.4
million. It wasn't going to happen. And
so um I just think this is a marriage
and I really appreciate the city council
uh seeing the vision of saving historic
buildings and um you know and being
willing to put the resources forward to
do that. So um if there's no other
comments, we'll take a vote.
All right. All those in favor of the
professional services agreement, please
signify by saying I.
>> I. Those opposed. The uh professional
services agreement is approved as
amended.
>> Next item is 19B on page four. Utility
easement agreement between the city of
Cheyenne and Microsoft Corporation for
grant of perpetual rideway and temporary
easement for underground fiber lines.
>> All right. Um we'll go out to the
audience. Does anybody want to talk
about an an easement with Microsoft for
uh some underground fiber lines
hearing? None. Mr. Esabel.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to approve an
amount of $10. And I so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White.
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Mr. Esabel.
>> I move to amend the amount of approval
to an amount of $1,265.
Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White.
All right. Anybody in the audience want
to speak to them paying us more money?
It's a good thing, right? All right. How
about from the governing body?
>> All those in favor, please signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Opposed.
>> The uh utility easement is approved as
amended.
[snorts]
>> Next item is number 22A on page five.
about your
>> report.
Did we didn't we didn't vote on the full
we vote on the amendment, not the actual
motion.
>> I think that might be true. Thank you.
So, we approved the substitute. Now,
we're back on the main motion.
>> Thank you. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed?
>> No.
>> All right. You said no.
>> Mr. Mr. Moody is a no.
The uh the public or the utility ement
is approved as amended. Thank you for
the catch. It is getting late.
>> Number 22A, voucher report.
>> Is there anybody in the audience or on
the governing body that would like to
speak to the vouchers?
>> Okay. Next item, please.
>> 22B, revenue report.
>> Anybody in the governing body or the
audience would like to speak to the
revenue report?
Next item, please.
>> Other business.
>> Mr. Hanland, I think this is your turn.
>> I thought it was going to be five hours,
so it was only two hours and 32 minutes.
So, you got off lucky tonight. Welcome,
sir.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I'm Ted Hanlin,
uh, resident of W 2 and as you probably
know, chair of the Larmy County
Democratic Party. Um,
some of my uh some of the residents of
Laramie County came to me last fall and
told me they weren't uh particularly
pleased with having flocked cameras. And
to be honest, I had no idea what they
were talking about. So, I I went out and
did some investigation. One of the
things I found in my investigation was
that uh the ACLU as opposed to the flot
cameras. I'm pretty fond of the ACLU's
ability to protect all of our rights, no
matter what side of the political divide
we're on. And so I did some more
investigation and that led me to create
an online petition which with your per
permission I will present the petition
and the signatures to you at the end of
my my little talk tonight. Um I'd just
like to uh read the petition into the
record.
You are being tracked. Without robust
public debate or a vote by the citizens,
the Cheyenne Police Department has
installed flock surveillance cameras
across our city, 23 and all. I think
there's actually more now. These are not
the standard white traffic cameras you
see at most intersections. They are
advanced license plate readers that
create a searchable database of where
you go, who you visit, and when you
leave your home.
This is a digital drag net that monitors
thousands of innocent Cheyenne residents
every day to catch a handful of
criminals.
We believe this is an overreach.
First, it's mass surveillance. The
government should not log the movements
of law-abiding citizens just in case a
crime happens.
Second, we have an issue with data
security. The data is stored by a
private company and can be shared with
agencies across the country, including
federal agencies, without a warrant.
And third, we're concern concerned with
a lack of oversight. There's no
independent judicial review of who is
searching this database or why.
We demand that Cheyenne remain a
community of neighbors, not suspects.
We call on you, Mr. mayor and the city
council to number one, halt the
expansion of the flock safety camera
network immediately.
Number two, remove existing cameras that
surveil residential neighborhoods. And
number three, pass a binding city
ordinance that prohibits the collection
of data on incident drivers without a
warrant and bans the sharing of local
data with federal agencies.
So, with your permission, Mr. Mayor, I'd
like to turn this over to you. We have
at this moment I I closed the um
petition tonight. We have 779 signatures
on the petition.
>> Thank you, Mr.
>> Thank you. I know it's late, but if
anybody has a question, I'll do my best
to answer a question.
>> We appreciate you being here this
evening. Thank you. Anybody else in the
audience want to speak under other
business?
All right. How about from the governing
body? Mr. Mayor, Mr. Labour,
[clears throat]
I know that these cameras have been a
matter of community discussion uh lately
and going back over a period of time,
but I want to emphasize that that
petition is riddled with inaccuracies
and falsehoods.
That is absolutely not the case. That's
not true. And the misleading of those
individuals to believe that those kind
of surveillance techniques that lead to
the things that were mentioned there are
something we support
is absolutely not only incorrect,
it's destructive.
Our police department does not do
anything like that.
And I I I want to particularly invite uh
these individuals that signed the
petition and the individual that
presented this to come to our meeting
next week at the public safety center
where the police department is going to
be able to thoroughly explain the uses
of those cameras, the history of those
cameras,
and the fact that they actually do
the very thing that they are set up to
do, which is catch people doing things
like carjackings,
robberies,
and that there is a very specific
set of circumstances that guarantee
that only the Cheyenne Police Department
looks at that.
So, I mean, there's a just and this was
something that came up recently here at
the library.
Um,
none of us, I'm sure,
[clears throat]
I guess I had to rephrase that. I assume
all of us are concerned about
surveillance.
Whether it's surveillance at the Mini
Mart when we're trying to buy something
or buy gas, whether it's surveillance at
uh a house that you go up and ring the
doorbell and they have a recording of
who who it is.
But I'll tell you what,
when you don't trust and don't believe
the facts
of our police department, that's a big
problem.
And the trust that we have to live with.
So, I want to emphasize this and Mr.
Hanland, I hope you'll come to this
meeting. It'll be announced soon,
but next week there's going to be a
meeting over in the public safety center
auditorium.
for a full and complete explanation
of what those cameras do, how they do
it, and why we why we hired him and the
history of them.
So, this isn't just uh
a vast system that follows people home.
And and we've had the same problem with
the uh other recent issues.
You know,
when when people absolutely believe
that we do the kinds of things that your
petition talks about, that's extremely
destructive to what we do. It's
destructive to the police department and
it's not true. So, I hope you'll uh be
sure to let your petitioners know that
they're going to have an opportunity
here next week to thoroughly review the
actual law, the law enforcement and how
it's administered and what those what
crimes
those Flock cameras have uh documented
and solved and who gets to see them and
the kind of work that's involved in
reviewing ing that data.
It's it's and and again, we just had a
complete
effort by individuals that were not
bringing this issue up that were not
specific to the program that we hired,
that were not specific to our police
department. So,
I'm very confident that it'll be a good
t thing for us or anyone else to go to
the public safety center, attend this
meeting, ask your questions, get your
answers, and understand what those
cameras do and what their use is because
it is completely and totally different
than your very misleading petition.
Thank you.
>> Anybody else in the governing body? Mr.
Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. May 3. Just wanted to say
congrats to our um athletes from the uh
Winter Olympics. Did pretty well in the
medal count and also both the women's
and men's hockey team. Great game and
glad to see them win gold. Thank you,
Mr. Mayor.
>> That was a good day. Dr. Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins through you. Um, I just
wanted to um remind everyone that the
last day to donate books um for the
Delta Capagama book sale, the um book
sale that's been going on our on in our
community for nearly 40 years now, uh is
March 1st. Um and you can drop those
book donations at the uh Vanderhigh
Beach, please at the Pickler at um the
Safeway on the south side of Cheyenne or
Albertson's on uh North Yellowstone. And
um so I look forward to seeing everyone
at the used book sale that will raise
money for uh numerous grants for
nonprofit uh youth organizations and
educational organizations in our
community.
>> Mr. Wolf.
>> Uh thank you Mr. Mayor through you. Um
just um just want to uh announce on
behalf of uh Councilman White and
Councilman Lebornne and myself that the
uh Ward Three uh will have our I mean W
three, Ward One, I'm sorry, uh Ward One
will have our council and coffee on
March 7th, uh which is Saturday morning
at 9:00 at the David Romero Center on
Parsley Boulevard. and um look forward
to anybody one, two or three who would
like to attend that and have an
opportunity to talk with us about
basically any topic. So thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um, in that regard
of these community uh events that we're
talking about here, I just want to
mention that recently at the [snorts] uh
beast facility that we acquired as a
city not too long ago, we had a really
wonderful, heartwarming
uh packed house of individuals who were
there for the taco and tequila uh
fundraiser for our KIA shelter.
And it was uh raised a lot of money.
There was a lot of volunteerism there.
And it was the kind of wonderful
wonderful things that happen in our
community in the effort to help unhoused
individuals.
And no, it's not enough.
And no, some people don't want to take
advantage of it. But what I see here is
a community that cares very much about
everyone
including individuals who are in
desperate desperate circumstances.
So it was uh certainly an occasion uh
for us to take a look at the positive
side of what we do and how we do it and
not uh the fact that we are somehow
spying on people and abusing their
rights. Um, not a direct relationship
there, but one that I found very
persuasive. We care, we work, and we try
to do the best. And that was one example
of that. And I would certainly uh
applaud the fact that we acquired the
beast for this type of a facility that
we uh supported KIO with the addition of
the stage coach Motel and worked towards
that and the grant processes. So, um I
guess it's just my personal uh feelings
and belief that uh there's an awful lot
of good things and a lot of good people
in this community and we represent them
imperfectly certainly
but sincerely. Thank you,
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um, I just wanted
to share with the community that today a
young woman in Rock Springs at Central
Wyoming College,
uh, honor student
um, honor student uh, on the student
body,
very beautiful young woman. um took her
own life in uh Rock Springs,
used a handgun and took her own life.
And I just want to remind everyone that
if they are considering suicide or need
any kind of crisis help, they can call
the suicide hotline at 988.
Um and hopefully we can save one person.
Thanks for that message.
>> Anyone else in the governing body? Mr.
Labour, do you have a motion for us?
>> Yes, I do. Mr. Mayor,
>> you were hoping the night was done, but
we have one more thing to do.
>> It kind of got buried here.
>> That's okay.
>> Mr. Mayor, pursuant to you turn your
microphone on for us. Thank you so much
that for sure. I thank you. Uh Mr.
Mayor, pursuant to Wyoming statute
164405A.
I move that the governing body meet in
executive session to consider or receive
any information classified as
confidential by law.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Mr. Labour and
seconded by was that Mr. Moody? By Mr.
Moody. Uh all those in favor of going
into executive session, please signify
by saying I. I.
>> I. Those opposed. All right, ladies and
gentlemen, we're going to move into
executive session. When we come out,
we're just going to adjourn. No other
business of the governing body will
happen. And we thank you for being here
this evening. At this time, we'll ask
you to leave so we can uh uh move into
an executive session.